REPORTER/O :/O --/O the/O 17th/O ./O 
This/O morning/O ,/O demonstrators/O blocked/O access/O to/O the/O Bryan/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION Building/ORGANIZATION ./O 
And/O after/O that/O ,/O picket/O lines/O were/O established/O around/O Ballantine/LOCATION and/O Rawles/LOCATION Halls/LOCATION ./O 
Five/O students/O met/O with/O a/O group/O of/O administrators/O this/O morning/O and/O agreed/O to/O maintain/O open/O picket/O lines/O ,/O permitting/O these/O students/O ,/O who/O desire/O to/O attend/O classes/O ,/O at/O least/O access/O until/O this/O meeting/O took/O place/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O coming/O onto/O the/O podium/O ,/O or/O onto/O the/O stage/O ,/O we/O see/O President/O Sutton/PERSON ,/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ,/O and/O the/O moderator/O of/O this/O afternoon/O 's/O meeting/O ,/O Professor/O of/O Law/PERSON Harry/PERSON Pratter/PERSON ./O 
Also/O seated/O on/O the/O stage/O is/O student/O body/O president/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Ladies/O and/O gentlemen/O ,/O my/O name/O is/O Harry/PERSON Pratter/PERSON ./O 
I/O 'm/O just/O a/O poor/O professor/O of/O law/O ./O 
And/O I/O hope/O to/O be/O able/O to/O be/O ,/O literally/O ,/O a/O moderator/O for/O this/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O 've/O been/O on/O the/O campus/O at/O Bryan/LOCATION Hall/LOCATION since/O 7:30/O in/O the/O morning/O ./O 
I/O know/O there/O are/O deep/O divisions/O among/O us/O ./O 
Quite/O frequently/O ,/O during/O the/O day/O ,/O when/O students/O were/O asked/O what/O their/O plans/O were/O and/O students/O were/O asked/O what/O 's/O likely/O to/O happen/O ,/O I/O heard/O one/O response/O ./O 
That/O response/O was/O it/O is/O up/O to/O the/O individual/O conscience/O of/O the/O person/O ./O 
It/O is/O up/O to/O his/O moral/O conscience/O ./O 
That/O explanation/O is/O appealing/O to/O me/O ./O 
I/O consider/O the/O moral/O conscience/O to/O be/O the/O most/O legitimate/O source/O of/O values/O and/O actions/O ./O 
And/O because/O I/O heard/O that/O phrase/O ,/O because/O I/O am/O committed/O to/O it/O ,/O I/O ,/O too/O ,/O want/O to/O appeal/O to/O your/O moral/O conscience/O ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O ,/O even/O though/O there/O are/O divisions/O among/O us/O --/O I/O understand/O that/O feelings/O are/O lacerated/O ./O 
I/O understand/O we/O are/O living/O in/O a/O tense/O world/O ./O 
I/O understand/O some/O of/O the/O ugliness/O that/O 's/O occurred/O on/O campuses/O and/O in/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O world/O ./O 
And/O I/O also/O understand/O that/O there/O is/O hope/O for/O the/O world/O --/O that/O there/O are/O occasions/O when/O certain/O differences/O must/O be/O set/O aside/O ./O 
If/O there/O is/O any/O chance/O of/O agreement/O of/O understanding/O of/O building/O a/O better/O world/O ,/O we/O must/O not/O lose/O those/O aspects/O of/O civilization/O we/O have/O gained/O for/O so/O long/O ./O 
This/O society/O is/O sick/O in/O very/O many/O ways/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O not/O incurable/O ./O 
And/O we/O are/O gathered/O together/O today/O to/O make/O one/O manifestation/O of/O rationality/O ./O 
We/O can/O learn/O ./O 
We/O can/O talk/O ./O 
We/O can/O discuss/O ./O 
We/O can/O exchange/O ./O 
We/O can/O --/O we/O 'll/O be/O better/O for/O it/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O your/O leader/O used/O the/O word/O \/O ``/O love/O \/O ''/O at/O Dunn/PERSON meadows/O ./O 
We/O use/O the/O word/O \/O ``/O peace/O ./O 
\/O ''/O We/O use/O the/O word/O \/O ``/O people/O ./O 
\/O ''/O And/O I/O ask/O you/O to/O remember/O those/O words/O ./O 
I/O ask/O you/O to/O convert/O this/O an/O occasion/O that/O we/O can/O all/O be/O proud/O of/O ./O 
First/O ,/O then/O ,/O will/O be/O a/O statement/O by/O President/O Sutton/PERSON ,/O then/O a/O statement/O by/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
Then/O ,/O I/O understand/O ,/O the/O student/O leaders/O will/O make/O statements/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O I/O hope/O to/O be/O able/O to/O recognize/O people/O from/O the/O floor/O ./O 
You/O recognize/O ,/O no/O matter/O how/O fair/O I/O want/O to/O be/O ,/O no/O matter/O how/O much/O I/O will/O want/O to/O recognize/O people/O of/O different/O views/O ,/O how/O difficult/O this/O will/O be/O for/O me/O ./O 
In/O a/O sense/O ,/O we/O must/O discipline/O ourselves/O in/O this/O audience/O ./O 
I/O should/O also/O announce/O that/O it/O 's/O the/O kind/O of/O meeting/O that/O we/O must/O have/O a/O time/O limit/O ./O 
It/O will/O be/O --/O there/O are/O issues/O which/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O can/O be/O --/O can/O --/O talked/O over/O and/O over/O again/O ./O 
I/O hope/O that/O ,/O in/O the/O hour/O allotted/O ,/O an/O hour/O from/O the/O first/O speaker/O ,/O we/O will/O be/O able/O to/O clarify/O enough/O ./O 
Let/O us/O see/O what/O happens/O in/O the/O hour/O ./O 
Let/O us/O agree/O ,/O at/O the/O first/O ,/O that/O we/O will/O last/O --/O talk/O --/O last/O for/O an/O hour/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O I/O think/O something/O has/O to/O be/O understood/O right/O now/O --/O that/O this/O meeting/O is/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O students/O ./O 
And/O I/O feel/O that/O for/O students/O to/O get/O as/O much/O out/O of/O this/O ,/O the/O moderator/O should/O be/O a/O student/O ./O 
And/O we/O can/O supply/O a/O student/O from/O the/O law/O school/O to/O moderate/O ,/O so/O the/O law/O school/O will/O still/O be/O in/O moderation/O ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O That/O was/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ,/O making/O a/O move/O that/O indicated/O that/O he/O wanted/O a/O student/O to/O moderate/O this/O afternoon/O 's/O meeting/O ./O 
There/O 's/O now/O a/O discussion/O taking/O place/O on/O the/O stage/O ,/O trying/O to/O decide/O --/O HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Mr./O Pryweller/PERSON is/O a/O student/O of/O mine/O ./O 
I/O am/O his/O teacher/O ./O 
We/O got/O along/O very/O well/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O he/O got/O --/O I/O think/O he/O got/O a/O B/O plus/O ,/O which/O is/O one/O of/O --/O --/O which/O is/O one/O of/O the/O highest/O grades/O I/O 've/O ever/O given/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O doubts/O about/O --/O in/O commercial/O law/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O dullest/O subjects/O ever/O taught/O ./O 
And/O if/O --/O if/O we/O could/O get/O along/O in/O that/O ,/O we/O can/O get/O along/O in/O moderating/O ./O 
And/O we/O will/O share/O these/O duties/O ./O 
We/O will/O be/O in/O constant/O consultation/O ,/O and/O we/O will/O --/O REPORTER/O :/O So/O a/O student/O ,/O Dale/PERSON Pryweller/PERSON ,/O a/O student/O of/O law/O ,/O will/O be/O sort/O of/O co-hosting/O the/O activities/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O We/O will/O fortify/O each/O other/O ./O 
And/O he/O will/O fortify/O me/O even/O more/O than/O I/O him/O ./O 
SPEAKER/O :/O Bullshit/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O ./O 
Hey/O ./O 
OK/O ./O 
We/O 're/O gon/O na/O --/O this/O is/O the/O format/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O follow/O ./O 
I/O 've/O got/O one/O announcement/O to/O make/O ./O 
And/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O hear/O short/O statements/O from/O President/O Sutton/PERSON and/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ,/O and/O then/O Keith/PERSON and/O Michael/PERSON will/O make/O short/O statements/O ./O 
And/O then/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O have/O a/O question/O and/O answer/O period/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O my/O announcement/O concerns/O what/O happened/O this/O morning/O ./O 
There/O were/O eight/O people/O that/O were/O arrested/O outside/O Bryan/LOCATION Hall/LOCATION ./O 
And/O they/O were/O all/O charged/O with/O a/O misdemeanor/O ,/O disorderly/O conduct/O ,/O except/O for/O one/O ,/O who/O is/O also/O charged/O with/O disregarding/O a/O police/O signal/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O bond/O --/O bond/O has/O been/O set/O at/O $/O 50/O ./O 
We/O need/O $/O 400/O at/O least/O for/O bond/O ./O 
And/O we/O need/O more/O than/O that/O for/O our/O defense/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O we/O 've/O got/O one/O of/O the/O law/O professors/O starting/O on/O the/O case/O ./O 
And/O he/O 's/O handled/O it/O so/O far/O ,/O Professor/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
Shornhorse/O ./O 
?/O -RSB-/O 
He/O 's/O handled/O a/O lot/O of/O student/O problems/O ./O 
He/O deserves/O around/O of/O applause/O ./O 
So/O those/O of/O you/O who/O were/O asked/O a/O little/O bit/O earlier/O if/O you/O have/O motorcycle/O helmets/O ,/O will/O you/O either/O pass/O them/O around/O yourselves/O ?/O 
Or/O will/O you/O given/O to/O nearby/O marshals/O ,/O who/O have/O white/O shirts/O and/O green/O bands/O and/O the/O moral/O force/O of/O marshals/O ,/O of/O course/O ?/O 
And/O while/O this/O whole/O thing/O is/O going/O on/O ,/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O try/O and/O raise/O some/O money/O and/O get/O those/O kids/O out/O of/O jail/O and/O back/O here/O with/O us/O ./O 
They/O were/O n't/O arrested/O fairly/O anyway/O ./O 
Yeah/O ./O 
Keith/PERSON says/O ,/O not/O nickels/O and/O dimes/O ./O 
We/O need/O some/O money/O ./O 
All/O the/O money/O is/O going/O to/O go/O to/O the/O Student/O Government/O Defense/O Fund/O ./O 
We/O 're/O going/O to/O use/O it/O for/O bail/O and/O defenses/O for/O stuff/O that/O happens/O around/O here/O on/O campus/O ./O 
OK/O ./O 
President/O Sutton/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O want/O to/O start/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Yes/O ./O 
First/O ,/O I/O wish/O to/O address/O myself/O to/O ,/O eh/O ,/O a/O statement/O attributed/O to/O me/O in/O ,/O eh/O ,/O various/O ways/O in/O the/O --/O in/O various/O newspapers/O ./O 
Can/O you/O hear/O me/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O No/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Oh/O ,/O sorry/O --/O attributed/O to/O me/O in/O various/O newspapers/O ./O 
And/O none/O of/O these/O newspapers/O '/O quotations/O seem/O to/O agree/O among/O themselves/O ./O 
This/O has/O to/O do/O with/O a/O speech/O which/O I/O gave/O in/O Evansville/LOCATION ,/O Indiana/LOCATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O you/O wo/O n't/O --/O if/O you/O wo/O n't/O think/O that/O I/O 'm/O ,/O I/O 'm/O indulging/O you/O or/O anything/O ,/O I/O will/O tell/O you/O ,/O uh/O ,/O what/O happened/O briefly/O ,/O and/O then/O tell/O you/O what/O ,/O uh/O ,/O I/O actually/O said/O in/O this/O connection/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Evansville/LOCATION ,/O Indiana/LOCATION ,/O to/O address/O an/O alumni/O group/O to/O talk/O about/O educational/O problems/O that/O I/O foresee/O in/O the/O year/O 2000/O ./O 
When/O I/O arrived/O --/O well/O ,/O I/O mean/O ,/O just/O bear/O with/O me/O ,/O please/O ./O 
And/O --/O and/O then/O you/O can/O hiss/O me/O when/O I/O 'm/O finished/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O well/O ,/O hiss/O me/O now/O if/O you/O like/O ,/O but/O --/O When/O I/O arrived/O ,/O I/O found/O that/O there/O was/O apprehension/O in/O ,/O among/O a/O significant/O number/O of/O people/O attending/O that/O meeting/O about/O what/O was/O going/O on/O in/O Bloomington/LOCATION ./O 
The/O question/O usually/O gets/O put/O to/O me/O ,/O what/O the/O hell/O is/O going/O on/O in/O Bloomington/LOCATION ?/O 
And/O so/O I/O addressed/O myself/O to/O that/O ,/O pointing/O out/O that/O what/O the/O hell/O was/O going/O on/O in/O Bloomington/LOCATION --/O and/O I/O 'm/O summarizing/O here/O --/O had/O ,/O A/O ,/O been/O peaceful/O ;/O B/O ,/O had/O been/O the/O result/O of/O the/O concern/O of/O not/O only/O ,/O uh/O ,/O young/O people/O who/O are/O considered/O to/O be/O on/O the/O left/O ,/O if/O there/O is/O such/O a/O thing/O ,/O but/O young/O people/O clear/O across/O the/O spectrum/O of/O political/O opinion/O ./O 
And/O the/O thing/O that/O concerned/O them/O was/O the/O war/O ./O 
And/O they/O were/O making/O a/O moral/O and/O peaceful/O protest/O to/O indicate/O their/O concern/O and/O ,/O in/O many/O cases/O ,/O their/O disdain/O for/O what/O was/O happening/O in/O Vietnam/LOCATION ./O 
I/O told/O them/O that/O they/O had/O every/O reason/O to/O be/O proud/O of/O the/O students/O and/O the/O entire/O academic/O community/O of/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O was/O followed/O --/O this/O is/O a/O summary/O ./O 
And/O ,/O and/O I/O --/O since/O I/O was/O giving/O it/O extemporaneously/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O have/O any/O notes/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O question/O and/O answer/O period/O ,/O uh/O ,/O following/O this/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O I/O should/O also/O add/O that/O I/O stated/O that/O it/O was/O the/O policy/O agreed/O upon/O by/O the/O administration/O that/O the/O university/O would/O remain/O open/O for/O those/O students/O who/O wished/O to/O attend/O ,/O that/O those/O students/O who/O did/O not/O wish/O to/O attend/O and/O who/O felt/O some/O moral/O obligation/O to/O go/O out/O and/O do/O something/O else/O --/O be/O it/O demonstrate/O or/O go/O back/O to/O their/O hometowns/O and/O talk/O to/O their/O elected/O representatives/O or/O their/O friends/O and/O neighbors/O and/O so/O on/O --/O ah/O ,/O were/O free/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O ah/O ,/O and/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O eh/O ,/O then/O there/O was/O --/O this/O was/O followed/O by/O a/O question/O and/O answer/O period/O ./O 
The/O question/O that/O elicited/O the/O unfortunate/O and/O conflicting/O quotations/O was/O the/O question/O would/O you/O ,/O under/O any/O circumstances/O ,/O close/O the/O university/O ?/O 
And/O my/O answer/O to/O that/O was/O not/O that/O ,/O ah/O ,/O after/O --/O I/O --/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O all/O the/O adjectives/O --/O bloody/O mayhem/O ,/O death/O ,/O and/O destruction/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ,/O had/O occurred/O ,/O but/O that/O I/O would/O certainly/O close/O the/O university/O ,/O on/O my/O own/O initiative/O ,/O if/O I/O felt/O that/O the/O lives/O of/O students/O ,/O faculty/O ,/O or/O citizens/O were/O endangered/O by/O any/O activity/O ,/O or/O if/O there/O were/O threats/O or/O possibilities/O of/O grave/O damage/O to/O property/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O that/O is/O what/O I/O said/O ./O 
And/O I/O want/O to/O get/O that/O cleared/O up/O ./O 
It/O was/O reported/O in/O one/O paper/O --/O I/O wo/O n't/O get/O into/O that/O ./O 
There/O were/O conflicting/O reports/O about/O what/O I/O said/O ./O 
But/O that/O is/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O uh/O ,/O not/O verbatim/O ,/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O the/O verbatim/O statement/O ./O 
But/O that/O is/O what/O I/O said/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O me/O get/O on/O to/O the/O second/O part/O of/O my/O statement/O ,/O because/O I/O know/O that/O you/O will/O have/O a/O lot/O of/O questions/O that/O you/O will/O wish/O to/O raise/O with/O both/O myself/O and/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O my/O obligation/O ,/O and/O indeed/O ,/O responsibility/O is/O to/O provide/O an/O educational/O opportunity/O ,/O eh/O ,/O in/O the/O classroom/O for/O those/O students/O who/O wish/O such/O an/O opportunity/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O feel/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O that/O I/O can/O close/O the/O university/O ,/O because/O these/O students/O who/O wish/O to/O attend/O classes/O --/O and/O there/O are/O many/O thousands/O --/O have/O paid/O their/O fees/O ,/O and/O have/O every/O right/O to/O expect/O that/O ,/O what/O they/O paid/O for/O ,/O they/O will/O get/O ./O 
It/O 's/O their/O bag/O ./O 
It/O 's/O what/O they/O want/O to/O do/O ./O 
It/O 's/O what/O the/O institution/O was/O originally/O set/O up/O to/O do/O ./O 
And/O that/O 's/O my/O obligation/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O --/O On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O feel/O that/O those/O students/O who/O ,/O out/O of/O reasons/O of/O conscience/O ,/O wish/O to/O go/O out/O and/O do/O something/O else/O ,/O providing/O it/O is/O ,/O does/O not/O interfere/O with/O the/O rights/O of/O others/O to/O do/O their/O thing/O ,/O should/O ,/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O be/O interfered/O with/O ./O 
And/O so/O long/O as/O they/O do/O not/O interfere/O with/O the/O rights/O of/O others/O to/O do/O their/O thing/O ,/O I/O feel/O it/O is/O the/O o/O --/O as/O much/O the/O obligation/O of/O the/O university/O to/O protect/O those/O who/O are/O doing/O something/O else/O as/O it/O is/O to/O protect/O those/O who/O attend/O class/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O 'll/O try/O to/O keep/O my/O --/O uh/O ,/O can/O you/O hear/O me/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Yes/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O 'll/O try/O to/O keep/O my/O comments/O relatively/O brief/O ,/O because/O they/O relate/O largely/O to/O a/O question/O of/O attitude/O relating/O to/O the/O ,/O to/O initially/O ,/O the/O student/O government/O demands/O ,/O which/O were/O made/O of/O the/O president/O sometime/O back/O on/O May/O 1/O ,/O and/O then/O followed/O by/O a/O referendum/O run/O by/O the/O students/O on/O this/O item/O ,/O which/O also/O went/O to/O faculty/O members/O and/O to/O staff/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O set/O of/O demands/O here/O ,/O and/O I/O want/O to/O speak/O to/O them/O very/O briefly/O ./O 
The/O first/O demand/O presented/O was/O that/O the/O university/O repudiate/O President/O Nixon/PERSON 's/O plans/O for/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O demand/O the/O immediate/O withdrawal/O --/O REPORTER/O :/O The/O crowd/O has/O risen/O to/O its/O feet/O as/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON read/O that/O one/O demand/O from/O the/O referendum/O ,/O and/O en/O masse/O ,/O let/O out/O a/O cheer/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O It/O 's/O obvious/O what/O your/O sentiment/O is/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O these/O demands/O were/O presented/O to/O the/O president/O of/O the/O university/O ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O speak/O first/O as/O a/O faculty/O member/O ,/O not/O as/O a/O chancellor/O ./O 
Had/O the/O president/O of/O this/O university/O made/O a/O statement/O in/O behalf/O of/O this/O university/O stating/O this/O kind/O of/O repudiation/O ,/O I/O would/O have/O moved/O a/O censure/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O have/O moved/O it/O for/O a/O damn/O simple/O reason/O ./O 
He/O 's/O appointed/O as/O president/O to/O preside/O over/O the/O educational/O policy/O and/O direction/O of/O this/O institution/O ,/O not/O to/O make/O statements/O for/O those/O of/O us/O on/O the/O faculty/O or/O among/O the/O students/O with/O relation/O to/O foreign/O policy/O ./O 
I/O think/O --/O I/O happen/O to/O personally/O hold/O that/O view/O of/O the/O faculty/O as/O well/O ./O 
The/O faculty/O is/O a/O corporate/O body/O concerned/O with/O scholarship/O and/O learning/O ./O 
Its/O function/O is/O different/O ./O 
It/O has/O a/O large/O --/O it/O has/O a/O large/O number/O of/O alternatives/O open/O for/O protest/O or/O demonstration/O at/O all/O kinds/O of/O matters/O which/O relate/O to/O political/O activities/O ,/O but/O not/O as/O a/O corporate/O body/O ./O 
Number/O two/O was/O to/O end/O the/O campus/O complicity/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION and/O open/O the/O books/O of/O the/O IU/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION to/O supply/O information/O on/O government/O contracts/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O The/O books/O of/O the/O IU/O Foundations/O on/O government/O contracts/O have/O been/O open/O for/O years/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O simple/O to/O get/O access/O to/O the/O records/O on/O government/O contracts/O of/O this/O university/O ./O 
One/O ,/O there/O are/O published/O lists/O which/O come/O out/O periodically/O identifying/O the/O contract/O ./O 
Secondly/O ,/O it/O is/O possible/O to/O examine/O the/O contract/O in/O the/O office/O of/O Dean/PERSON Merritt/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O thing/O that/O is/O withheld/O on/O the/O statement/O of/O the/O contracts/O is/O those/O sections/O of/O the/O budget/O which/O relate/O to/O the/O individual/O salaries/O of/O investigators/O ./O 
This/O has/O been/O the/O case/O here/O for/O years/O ./O 
And/O year/O after/O year/O ,/O we/O have/O had/O to/O repeat/O the/O same/O message/O ./O 
The/O books/O on/O government/O contracts/O are/O open/O ./O 
Number/O three/O ,/O with/O relation/O to/O the/O financial/O commitment/O to/O the/O Bobby/ORGANIZATION Seale/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION Fund/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O is/O a/O simple/O thing/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Individual/O students/O ,/O faculty/O ,/O and/O others/O can/O make/O contributions/O to/O this/O Defense/O Fund/O ./O 
It/O is/O illegal/O to/O take/O general/O fund/O money/O and/O make/O contributions/O of/O this/O kind/O ./O 
I/O personally/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O go/O to/O Michigan/LOCATION City/LOCATION right/O now/O ./O 
Number/O four/O dealt/O with/O bringing/O --/O increasing/O the/O percentage/O of/O black/O students/O in/O the/O university/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O percentage/O of/O the/O black/O people/O in/O the/O state/O of/O Indiana/LOCATION ./O 
I/O am/O --/O I/O 'm/O shocked/O that/O you/O applaud/O ./O 
Why/O not/O more/O ?/O 
The/O blunt/O truth/O of/O the/O matter/O --/O The/O blunt/O truth/O of/O the/O matter/O is/O that/O we/O have/O been/O working/O on/O increasing/O the/O number/O of/O black/O students/O in/O this/O university/O ./O 
Vice/O Chancellor/O Herman/PERSON Hudson/PERSON and/O I/O are/O now/O to/O prepare/O a/O plan/O to/O try/O to/O further/O increase/O the/O number/O of/O black/O students/O ./O 
I/O think/O there/O is/O a/O mythology/O here/O that/O you/O want/O to/O set/O quotas/O ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O set/O quotas/O ./O 
You/O want/O to/O take/O people/O in/O and/O educate/O them/O ./O 
And/O you/O want/O to/O increase/O numbers/O ./O 
We/O know/O that/O we/O have/O a/O smaller/O proportionate/O number/O of/O black/O students/O now/O than/O we/O had/O in/O the/O 1950s/O ./O 
Our/O intention/O is/O to/O do/O something/O about/O it/O ./O 
And/O we/O 've/O been/O meeting/O with/O the/O black/O student/O leaders/O on/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Let/O 's/O let/O him/O finish/O up/O what/O he/O has/O to/O say/O ,/O please/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O We/O have/O met/O with/O the/O black/O student/O leaders/O on/O it/O ./O 
And/O we/O are/O working/O constructively/O at/O it/O ./O 
The/O other/O thing/O that/O ended/O on/O the/O referendum/O was/O to/O close/O the/O university/O ./O 
The/O student/O vote/O was/O 9,000/O plus/O to/O 7,000/O plus/O yes/O ./O 
The/O faculty/O vote/O was/O three/O quarters/O plus/O no/O ./O 
The/O blunt/O truth/O of/O the/O matter/O is/O ,/O however/O ,/O why/O should/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O wish/O to/O go/O on/O be/O turned/O off/O by/O the/O fact/O of/O the/O majority/O rule/O ?/O 
I/O am/O not/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Come/O on/O ./O 
Can/O we/O have/O a/O little/O quiet/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Now/O ,/O President/O Sutton/PERSON has/O spoken/O before/O of/O our/O concern/O that/O those/O who/O really/O wish/O to/O withdraw/O from/O the/O classes/O and/O do/O other/O things/O of/O a/O constructive/O nature/O in/O relation/O to/O making/O their/O political/O positions/O known/O ,/O that/O we/O are/O concerned/O to/O protect/O their/O rights/O ./O 
I/O am/O quite/O willing/O to/O say/O that/O I/O will/O ,/O I/O find/O the/O faculty/O council/O resolution/O passed/O yesterday/O urging/O the/O faculty/O to/O pay/O particular/O attention/O to/O this/O and/O to/O take/O steps/O when/O they/O can/O to/O provide/O that/O academic/O penalties/O are/O not/O felt/O by/O the/O students/O ./O 
There/O is/O ,/O however/O ,/O a/O myth/O in/O this/O system/O which/O I/O find/O startling/O --/O that/O administrators/O can/O issue/O orders/O to/O faculty/O about/O this/O ./O 
They/O ca/O n't/O ,/O and/O they/O never/O have/O been/O able/O to/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Um/O ,/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O before/O Keith/PERSON and/O Mike/PERSON speak/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O do/O one/O other/O thing/O ./O 
I/O lied/O ./O 
I/O 'd/O like/O to/O read/O you/O the/O names/O of/O those/O people/O who/O were/O arrested/O ,/O and/O tell/O you/O that/O ,/O if/O any/O of/O you/O know/O anything/O --/O if/O you/O were/O a/O witness/O ,/O if/O you/O were/O there/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O these/O people/O ,/O you/O saw/O something/O --/O go/O to/O the/O student/O government/O office/O and/O write/O down/O on/O a/O piece/O of/O paper/O who/O you/O are/O ,/O where/O we/O can/O get/O in/O touch/O with/O you/O ,/O what/O you/O were/O doing/O while/O you/O were/O there/O ,/O names/O ,/O anything/O you/O can/O remember/O ./O 
While/O I/O 'm/O reading/O the/O names/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O invite/O President/O Sutton/PERSON ,/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ,/O and/O Mr./O Pratter/PERSON to/O contribute/O to/O our/O fund/O ./O 
Those/O --/O those/O people/O arrested/O --/O REPORTER/O :/O Currently/O ,/O President/O Sutton/PERSON and/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON have/O refused/O that/O invitation/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Those/O --/O those/O people/O arrested/O were/O William/PERSON Curley/PERSON ,/O Paul/PERSON Dobbs/PERSON ,/O Susan/PERSON Young/PERSON ,/O Gregory/PERSON Hess/PERSON ,/O Steve/PERSON Emery/PERSON ,/O Roger/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Nalton/PERSON ,/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Mike/PERSON Jones/PERSON ,/O and/O John/PERSON Cowles/PERSON ./O 
I/O hope/O we/O can/O all/O give/O them/O our/O moral/O and/O any/O kind/O of/O support/O you/O can/O give/O them/O ./O 
OK/O ./O 
Our/O next/O speaker/O is/O Vice/O President/O of/O of/O the/O Student/O Body/O ,/O Mike/PERSON King/PERSON ./O 
MIKE/PERSON KING/PERSON :/O Forgive/O me/O if/O I/O --/O if/O this/O takes/O a/O little/O time/O ./O 
There/O 's/O --/O there/O 's/O quite/O a/O bit/O of/O a/O correction/O in/O addition/O to/O the/O minutes/O to/O be/O made/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O talk/O first/O about/O President/O Sutton/PERSON 's/O statement/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O said/O ,/O uh/O ,/O as/O near/O as/O I/O can/O figure/O is/O ,/O is/O true/O ,/O although/O the/O tone/O of/O his/O statement/O was/O a/O little/O different/O when/O it/O was/O read/O yesterday/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O and/O there/O 's/O some/O ,/O some/O things/O that/O he/O did/O leave/O out/O that/O I/O think/O people/O should/O know/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O and/O we/O have/O contacted/O the/O Evansville/LOCATION press/O ./O 
And/O ,/O uh/O ,/O they/O have/O told/O us/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O he/O can/O deny/O it/O all/O he/O wants/O ,/O but/O it/O 's/O our/O word/O against/O his/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O this/O is/O ,/O this/O is/O from/O the/O Evansville/LOCATION press/O ,/O a/O reporter/O ,/O uh/O ,/O willing/O to/O testify/O to/O these/O notes/O that/O she/O took/O ,/O exact/O quote/O here/O ./O 
He/O told/O the/O alumni/O that/O IU/O will/O remain/O open/O unless/O ,/O and/O I/O quote/O ,/O great/O violence/O causing/O bodily/O harm/O or/O possible/O death/O and/O grievous/O property/O damages/O forces/O me/O to/O close/O it/O ./O 
But/O it/O will/O be/O bloody/O mayhem/O before/O I/O will/O close/O it/O ./O 
And/O if/O I/O close/O it/O ,/O I/O will/O close/O it/O good/O and/O proper/O ./O 
And/O this/O is/O something/O left/O out/O here/O ./O 
Salaries/O will/O cease/O and/O things/O will/O come/O to/O a/O standstill/O ./O 
And/O it/O will/O stay/O closed/O till/O I/O 'm/O good/O and/O ready/O to/O open/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O appointed/O president/O of/O the/O university/O to/O deny/O anybody/O the/O right/O to/O an/O education/O ,/O no/O matter/O how/O reasonable/O or/O how/O short/O a/O strike/O request/O is/O ,/O is/O sought/O ./O 
I/O will/O not/O permit/O it/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O 's/O not/O --/O it/O 's/O not/O only/O students/O that/O were/O a/O little/O upset/O about/O this/O statement/O ./O 
Faculty/O were/O a/O little/O upset/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O there/O 's/O so/O many/O first/O person/O pronouns/O here/O ./O 
Um/O --/O But/O I/O think/O some/O of/O the/O other/O things/O that/O were/O mentioned/O here/O ,/O uh/O ,/O during/O his/O talk/O are/O a/O little/O instructive/O ./O 
This/O is/O from/O the/O Evansville/ORGANIZATION Courier/ORGANIZATION now/O under/O a/O headline/O ,/O \/O ``/O IU/O President/O Determined/O to/O Keep/O His/O School/O Open/O ./O 
\/O ''/O Um/O ,/O although/O there/O are/O a/O couple/O of/O students/O in/O the/O IU/O student/O government/O whom/O Sutton/PERSON admittedly/O does/O n't/O like/O ,/O he/O said/O the/O leaders/O so/O far/O have/O asked/O students/O to/O obey/O rules/O and/O avoid/O violence/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O believe/O it/O ./O 
It/O may/O not/O last/O ./O 
But/O it/O has/O up/O till/O --/O up/O until/O now/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O the/O IU/O students/O generally/O do/O n't/O like/O the/O present/O student/O government/O ,/O whose/O leader/O calls/O himself/O a/O self-styled/O Black/O Panther/O militant/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O and/O it/O goes/O on/O ,/O talking/O about/O how/O ,/O uh/O ,/O students/O ran/O Mark/PERSON off/O campus/O ./O 
And/O then/O ,/O here/O 's/O another/O section/O ./O 
It/O 's/O --/O it/O 's/O kind/O of/O useful/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O people/O who/O were/O arrested/O today/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O he/O believes/O there/O are/O about/O --/O and/O this/O was/O also/O in/O the/O ./O 
People/O can/O check/O on/O this/O too/O ./O 
And/O --/O and/O ,/O uh/O ,/O you/O can/O check/O with/O the/O reporters/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O he/O believes/O that/O there/O are/O about/O 50/O students/O on/O the/O IU/LOCATION campus/O dedicated/O to/O violent/O destructive/O acts/O --/O --/O who/O may/O be/O able/O to/O raise/O 200/O to/O 400/O more/O for/O additional/O support/O ./O 
The/O rest/O are/O fine/O young/O men/O and/O women/O who/O are/O concerned/O about/O the/O war/O and/O other/O problems/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O point/O out/O that/O whoever/O those/O 50/O students/O are/O dedicated/O to/O violent/O destructive/O acts/O ,/O that/O they/O 're/O not/O uniformed/O ,/O that/O they/O do/O not/O carry/O four/O foot/O clubs/O ./O 
They/O are/O not/O dressed/O up/O in/O riot/O gear/O ,/O that/O they/O do/O not/O have/O --/O --/O that/O they/O do/O not/O have/O two/O half/O tracks/O poised/O on/O the/O edge/O of/O town/O ,/O as/O was/O done/O last/O week/O ,/O uh/O ,/O by/O state/O police/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O and/O if/O any/O vi/O --/O violence/O comes/O to/O this/O campus/O ,/O that/O 's/O where/O it/O 's/O going/O to/O come/O from/O ,/O those/O police/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O he/O said/O he/O has/O heard/O talk/O that/O some/O ou/O --/O some/O of/O the/O out/O of/O town/O students/O believe/O ,/O uh/O ,/O believe/O if/O IU/O stays/O open/O ,/O it/O will/O break/O the/O national/O strike/O ./O 
Sutton/PERSON said/O ,/O there/O is/O no/O way/O of/O telling/O who/O are/O the/O out/O of/O town/O students/O ./O 
Luckily/O ,/O Bloomington/LOCATION is/O a/O small/O town/O ,/O and/O can/O not/O accommodate/O many/O out/O of/O town/O people/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O now/O ,/O before/O I/O lean/O into/O this/O next/O part/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O emphasize/O ,/O um/O ,/O um/O ,/O that/O in/O two/O meetings/O that/O Keith/PERSON and/O I/O had/O with/O the/O president/O ,/O and/O ,/O and/O ,/O uh/O ,/O as/O ,/O as/O ,/O you/O heard/O him/O say/O again/O today/O ,/O uh/O ,/O that/O he/O would/O n/O --/O not/O make/O a/O statement/O on/O foreign/O policy/O ,/O and/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O not/O even/O as/O an/O individual/O ,/O because/O ,/O because/O he/O knew/O --/O --/O he/O knew/O ,/O he/O knew/O that/O his/O name/O could/O not/O be/O dissociated/O from/O the/O fact/O that/O he/O was/O president/O of/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O he/O made/O that/O statement/O to/O Keith/PERSON and/O I/O ,/O uh/O ,/O twice/O ./O 
And/O ,/O and/O he/O 's/O been/O making/O it/O repeatedly/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O this/O is/O what/O occurred/O ,/O uh/O ,/O at/O the/O Evansville/LOCATION alumni/O meeting/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Evansville/ORGANIZATION Courier/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Students/O have/O asked/O him/O to/O denounce/O the/O move/O into/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O 
But/O Sutton/PERSON ,/O who/O lived/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION for/O three/O years/O as/O a/O special/O advisor/O to/O the/O government/O ,/O said/O ,/O quote/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O even/O have/O the/O facts/O yet/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O a/O professional/O in/O this/O field/O ,/O and/O I/O can/O not/O make/O a/O decision/O without/O the/O facts/O ,/O end/O quote/O ./O 
And/O then/O ,/O and/O then/O the/O final/O statement/O of/O ,/O uh/O ,/O the/O article/O ,/O which/O is/O not/O a/O direct/O quote/O --/O and/O we/O 're/O trying/O to/O run/O down/O a/O direct/O quote/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O he/O personally/O favors/O the/O move/O himself/O ,/O although/O he/O would/O not/O make/O such/O a/O statement/O as/O the/O IU/O president/O ,/O this/O after/O promising/O that/O he/O would/O never/O make/O such/O a/O statement/O ./O 
So/O that/O it/O is/O not/O a/O question/O here/O of/O a/O apolitical/O university/O versus/O politics/O invading/O the/O university/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O question/O of/O Mr./O Sutton/PERSON 's/O politics/O versus/O the/O politics/O of/O the/O people/O of/O university/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O say/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O statement/O that/O Keith/PERSON and/O I/O released/O yesterday/O ,/O that/O this/O meeting/O ,/O uh/O ,/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
is/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
the/O responsibility/O of/O many/O other/O concerned/O student/O ./O 
I/O was/O ,/O I/O was/O home/O preparing/O for/O a/O class/O when/O I/O found/O out/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O friends/O of/O mine/O had/O been/O arrested/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O I/O ,/O I/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O say/O that/O --/O I/O want/O --/O I/O was/O ,/O I/O was/O proud/O of/O those/O students/O taking/O a/O stand/O ./O 
I/O was/O proud/O of/O the/O faculty/O taking/O a/O stand/O out/O there/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O it/O 's/O about/O time/O the/O rest/O of/O university/O takes/O a/O stand/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O gon/O na/O give/O it/O back/O to/O Sutton/PERSON and/O Carter/PERSON after/O you/O speak/O ./O 
./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O My/O co-moderator/O and/O I/O agree/O that/O President/O Sutton/PERSON should/O have/O an/O opportunity/O to/O respond/O before/O Mr./O Parker/PERSON makes/O his/O remarks/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O No/O !/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O I/O did/O not/O say/O I/O --/O I/O ,/O I/O made/O no/O --/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O made/O no/O comment/O ,/O pro/O or/O con/O ,/O on/O the/O present/O campaign/O in/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O get/O to/O questions/O in/O a/O second/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O we/O have/O one/O more/O speaker/O ,/O a/O man/O whose/O conduct/O has/O ,/O has/O been/O exemplary/O in/O the/O past/O weekend/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O the/O --/O President/O of/O your/O student/O body/O ,/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O The/O audience/O is/O once/O again/O rising/O to/O its/O feet/O in/O a/O greeting/O to/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O sitting/O quietly/O at/O the/O edge/O of/O the/O table/O set/O up/O on/O stage/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O president/O of/O the/O student/O body/O ,/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O All/O I/O can/O say/O to/O that/O is/O right/O on/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O on/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O what/O I/O have/O to/O say/O will/O not/O take/O much/O time/O ,/O because/O I/O think/O ,/O uh/O ,/O Mike/PERSON has/O said/O ,/O uh/O ,/O enough/O ./O 
And/O I/O 've/O said/O enough/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O now/O ,/O many/O of/O you/O have/O things/O to/O say/O that/O are/O closer/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O to/O what/O needs/O to/O be/O said/O ,/O and/O are/O very/O important/O also/O ./O 
But/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O speak/O first/O to/O ,/O uh/O ,/O one/O part/O of/O the/O demands/O ,/O the/O demand/O on/O Bobby/PERSON Seale/PERSON --/O that/O we/O never/O said/O money/O would/O be/O taken/O out/O of/O the/O general/O fund/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O to/O implement/O this/O ./O 
We/O said/O that/O means/O would/O be/O made/O to/O raise/O money/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O people/O of/O Indiana/LOCATION ,/O no/O matter/O how/O beautiful/O they/O may/O be/O ,/O are/O not/O yet/O at/O the/O point/O where/O they/O can/O relate/O to/O chipping/O into/O Bobby/PERSON Seale/PERSON 's/O Defense/O Fund/O ./O 
Now/O --/O so/O this/O is/O why/O we/O --/O we/O understood/O this/O clearly/O from/O the/O start/O ,/O and/O had/O in/O our/O heads/O that/O 'd/O be/O means/O to/O raise/O money/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O in/O terms/O of/O the/O statement/O that/O Mike/PERSON and/O I/O made/O yesterday/O --/O and/O I/O said/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O I/O said/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O well/O ,/O if/O Mike/PERSON and/O I/O have/O to/O be/O policemen/O ,/O then/O we/O might/O as/O well/O move/O into/O Bryan/PERSON Hall/PERSON ./O 
What/O I/O was/O speaking/O in/O terms/O of/O was/O that/O I/O think/O --/O and/O I/O 've/O said/O this/O enough/O times/O --/O that/O if/O Mike/PERSON and/O I/O are/O going/O to/O have/O to/O do/O all/O these/O jobs/O on/O campus/O ,/O that/O our/O offices/O might/O as/O well/O be/O in/O the/O president/O 's/O office/O in/O Bryan/PERSON 200/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O on/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O --/O and/O if/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O on/O ./O 
And/O I/O 'll/O say/O it/O again/O ./O 
And/O if/O those/O offices/O were/O up/O for/O election/O ,/O Mike/PERSON and/O I/O would/O run/O for/O those/O too/O ./O 
So/O the/O purpose/O ,/O the/O purpose/O of/O people/O being/O here/O today/O is/O to/O once/O run/O what/O is/O on/O their/O minds/O directly/O to/O those/O people/O who/O should/O have/O some/O answers/O ./O 
And/O everyone/O has/O to/O understand/O this/O ./O 
Everyone/O has/O to/O understand/O that/O you/O do/O have/O a/O right/O to/O speak/O out/O ,/O that/O no/O one/O can/O deny/O you/O this/O right/O ./O 
And/O if/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O want/O to/O attend/O classes/O are/O to/O be/O protected/O ,/O then/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O want/O to/O speak/O out/O must/O be/O protected/O ./O 
So/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O take/O up/O too/O much/O more/O time/O ./O 
But/O all/O I/O 'm/O gon/O na/O say/O is/O that/O I/O 'm/O still/O on/O strike/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O on/O ./O 
Right/O on/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O And/O to/O those/O beautiful/O people/O at/O Bryan/PERSON and/O at/O Ballantine/LOCATION and/O all/O around/O today/O ,/O all/O power/O to/O the/O people/O ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O You/O 're/O listening/O to/O live/O coverage/O of/O the/O student/O administration/O forum/O ./O 
We/O now/O pause/O 10/O seconds/O for/O station/O identification/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O We/O 'll/O --/O we/O 'll/O get/O questions/O from/O the/O floor/O ./O 
And/O uh/O ,/O are/O the/O ,/O are/O the/O floor/O microphones/O on/O ?/O 
Do/O they/O have/O enough/O lead/O to/O carry/O them/O back/O to/O people/O who/O ,/O uh/O ,/O want/O to/O speak/O ?/O 
REPORTER/O :/O We/O no/O questions/O being/O accepted/O from/O the/O floor/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O If/O you/O ca/O n't/O get/O to/O a/O microphone/O and/O shout/O loud/O enough/O for/O us/O up/O here/O to/O hear/O ,/O we/O can/O repeat/O your/O question/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Can/O I/O be/O recognized/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
I/O 'd/O like/O to/O speak/O for/O the/O students/O that/O want/O an/O education/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O You/O will/O have/O your/O chance/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O principally/O ,/O this/O was/O to/O be/O a/O question/O and/O answer/O session/O for/O President/O Sutton/PERSON and/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
So/O if/O we/O could/O keep/O to/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O everybody/O here/O would/O appreciate/O it/O ./O 
I/O know/O they/O would/O ./O 
Right/O in/O the/O front/O in/O the/O middle/O ./O 
Yell/O your/O question/O while/O we/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O My/O ,/O my/O question/O is/O to/O the/O people/O who/O are/O leading/O the/O strike/O ./O 
./O 
My/O question/O is/O to/O the/O people/O who/O are/O leading/O the/O strike/O ./O 
With/O all/O this/O glorious/O rhetoric/O about/O respecting/O people/O 's/O rights/O ,/O I/O 'm/O wondering/O ,/O seriously/O ,/O what/O action/O is/O to/O be/O taken/O by/O the/O student/O government/O ,/O that/O is/O obviously/O leading/O the/O strike/O ,/O to/O stop/O people/O from/O pushing/O people/O ,/O which/O is/O assault/O and/O battery/O ,/O I/O understand/O ,/O pushing/O people/O ,/O pushing/O bricks/O at/O people/O ,/O and/O closing/O doors/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O is/O a/O violation/O of/O rights/O ./O 
And/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O know/O what/O 's/O going/O to/O be/O done/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O ,/O Mike/PERSON ./O 
MIKE/PERSON KING/PERSON :/O Yeah/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O the/O strike/O today/O goes/O ,/O you/O 'll/O have/O to/O talk/O to/O people/O that/O were/O running/O the/O strike/O ,/O that/O were/O on/O strike/O lines/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O at/O --/O student/O government/O was/O not/O ./O 
But/O I/O want/O to/O say/O --/O I/O want/O to/O say/O a/O little/O bit/O about/O ,/O uh/O --/O I/O want/O to/O say/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O I/O was/O picketing/O on/O Friday/O ./O 
And/O ,/O uh/O ,/O I/O was/O pushed/O around/O and/O shoved/O around/O and/O assaulted/O around/O ,/O as/O ,/O as/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O these/O ,/O these/O ,/O uh/O ,/O uh/O ,/O as/O ,/O as/O much/O as/O ,/O uh/O ,/O scabs/O were/O ,/O uh/O ,/O by/O scabs/O going/O through/O the/O line/O ./O 
I/O think/O --/O I/O think/O that/O ,/O you/O know/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Can/O we/O give/O her/O the/O microphone/O and/O let/O her/O ,/O um/O --/O she/O --/O she/O wants/O ,/O she/O wants/O to/O sharpen/O the/O question/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O want/O an/O answer/O to/O this/O question/O ./O 
You/O are/O demanding/O that/O the/O administration/O give/O answers/O ./O 
You/O 're/O demanding/O that/O the/O administration/O give/O action/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O some/O action/O that/O prevents/O my/O not/O going/O to/O class/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O hold/O this/O mic/O and/O represent/O the/O people/O who/O have/O not/O been/O heard/O from/O until/O I/O get/O an/O answer/O for/O action/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O about/O the/O people/O dying/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Let/O 's/O keep/O on/O this/O issue/O ,/O all/O right/O ?/O 
We/O 'll/O raise/O one/O at/O a/O time/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O As/O we/O clearly/O said/O ,/O picket/O lines/O are/O picket/O lines/O ./O 
They/O 'll/O be/O defined/O by/O the/O picketers/O ./O 
We/O do/O not/O have/O individual/O strings/O on/O every/O picketer/O ./O 
We/O made/O it/O clear/O --/O we/O made/O it/O clear/O that/O they/O would/O de/O --/O be/O defined/O by/O such/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O we/O call/O for/O open/O picket/O lines/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O people/O decide/O that/O they/O believe/O strong/O enough/O to/O close/O those/O lines/O ,/O it/O is/O their/O choice/O ./O 
And/O that/O 's/O all/O I/O got/O ta/O say/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O my/O rights/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Um/O --/O HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON wants/O to/O respond/O to/O that/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON will/O respond/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O May/O I/O simply/O say/O that/O I/O 'm/O in/O full/O agreement/O with/O you/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O hope/O if/O you/O have/O these/O difficulties/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O they/O can/O hear/O you/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O You/O will/O let/O us/O know/O --/O that/O the/O truth/O of/O the/O matter/O is/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O see/O how/O ,/O in/O the/O name/O of/O X/O against/O repression/O ,/O you/O repress/O people/O ./O 
And/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O that/O this/O has/O happened/O on/O some/O of/O the/O closed/O picket/O lines/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O In/O the/O --/O in/O the/O yellow/O shirt/O ./O 
Behind/O you/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Behind/O you/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O have/O a/O question/O for/O the/O ,/O uh/O ,/O for/O the/O president/O and/O the/O chancellor/O ./O 
Now/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Can/O somebody/O pass/O him/O a/O mic/O ?/O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O We/O 'll/O repeat/O it/O ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Go/O ahead/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O the/O faculty/O ,/O as/O you/O said/O ,/O voted/O three/O quarters/O plus/O in/O support/O of/O President/O Nixon/PERSON 's/O Cambodian/O invasion/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O Is/O that/O true/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O No/O ,/O no/O ,/O no/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O The/O --/O the/O factual/O premise/O is/O wrong/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O rephrase/O your/O question/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O voted/O against/O invasion/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Yes/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O do/O n't/O have/O a/O question/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O The/O question/O has/O been/O answered/O ./O 
In/O the/O ,/O uh/O --/O This/O gentleman/O right/O there/O ./O 
MAN/O :/O Mr./O Chairman/O ?/O 
OK/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O I/O called/O on/O him/O ./O 
You/O 'll/O be/O next/O ./O 
You/O can/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
I/O 'd/O like/O to/O know/O exactly/O faculty/O administrative/O policy/O ./O 
Are/O the/O students/O who/O do/O choose/O to/O not/O attend/O classes/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Just/O so/O you/O wo/O n't/O think/O I/O 'm/O ducking/O the/O issue/O ,/O I/O will/O tell/O you/O this/O ./O 
At/O the/O last/O Bloomington/LOCATION council/O meeting/O ,/O this/O --/O this/O policy/O is/O decided/O campus/O by/O campus/O ,/O and/O we/O have/O seven/O ./O 
At/O the/O last/O Bloomington/LOCATION campus/O meeting/O ,/O the/O Bloomington/LOCATION faculty/O council/O took/O action/O and/O made/O a/O recommendation/O to/O the/O faculty/O at/O large/O ./O 
And/O I/O will/O now/O --/O uh/O ,/O uh/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O oppose/O this/O recommendation/O ./O 
And/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O it/O is/O quite/O in/O accordance/O with/O academic/O tradition/O ,/O as/O I/O have/O known/O it/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON will/O give/O you/O the/O details/O if/O you/O would/O allow/O him/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O quickly/O ,/O what/O was/O passed/O was/O a/O resolution/O which/O essentially/O urged/O that/O faculty/O pay/O serious/O attention/O to/O finding/O means/O by/O which/O students/O would/O not/O suffer/O undue/O academic/O penalties/O for/O participation/O in/O political/O protest/O ,/O for/O going/O back/O home/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O to/O talk/O to/O people/O ./O 
The/O options/O on/O this/O are/O not/O spelled/O out/O in/O the/O faculty/O council/O resolution/O ,/O because/O the/O various/O divisions/O of/O the/O Bloomington/LOCATION campus/O have/O different/O kinds/O of/O rule/O patterns/O on/O parts/O of/O their/O grades/O ./O 
The/O College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION Policy/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O I/O understand/O ,/O already/O made/O some/O suggestions/O --/O DALE/O PRYWELLER/O :/O Yeah/O ,/O I/O know/O who/O he/O is/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O --/O connecting/O with/O this/O ./O 
The/O law/O school/O faculty/O was/O prepared/O to/O meet/O on/O this/O today/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O business/O school/O faculty/O is/O about/O to/O meet/O ./O 
And/O there/O are/O various/O alternatives/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O you/O may/O get/O different/O things/O developed/O in/O different/O places/O ./O 
Obviously/O ,/O the/O incomplete/O is/O one/O ,/O with/O a/O deferred/O examination/O ./O 
That/O might/O be/O a/O possibility/O ./O 
It/O 's/O easy/O to/O do/O for/O an/O instructor/O ./O 
Some/O pass-fail/O relationships/O may/O be/O done/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O there/O are/O various/O options/O that/O are/O open/O ./O 
But/O it/O is/O up/O to/O the/O individual/O faculty/O member/O to/O accept/O the/O recommendations/O which/O come/O to/O him/O ,/O because/O grading/O practices/O around/O here/O have/O always/O stayed/O with/O the/O individual/O faculty/O member/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O Chuck/PERSON Turner/PERSON was/O next/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O Yes/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O --/O I/O --/O I/O have/O ,/O uh/O ,/O at/O least/O two/O questions/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O ask/O ./O 
And/O the/O first/O one/O has/O to/O do/O with/O nonviolence/O ./O 
We/O 've/O heard/O a/O great/O deal/O about/O non/O --/O nonviolence/O on/O this/O campus/O ./O 
And/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O know/O who/O is/O responsible/O for/O calling/O police/O onto/O this/O campus/O ./O 
We/O --/O we/O have/O --/O we/O have/O it/O from/O Mayor/O Hooker/PERSON that/O someone/O in/O the/O administration/O invited/O police/O onto/O this/O campus/O ./O 
Is/O that/O true/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O No/O matter/O who/O called/O the/O police/O on/O this/O campus/O --/O wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
I/O am/O ultimately/O responsible/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Well/O ,/O who/O did/O it/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Because/O I/O 'm/O president/O of/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O Sir/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Hey/O ,/O can/O we/O --/O can/O we/O let/O Chuck/PERSON ask/O his/O question/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Blame/O me/O ,/O I/O 'm/O saying/O ./O 
Yeah/O ,/O you/O can/O blame/O me/O for/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Who/O called/O them/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Chuck/PERSON CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O There/O is/O great/O sentiment/O on/O campus/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O much/O of/O the/O responsibility/O for/O what/O violence/O there/O w/O --/O was/O that/O did/O occur/O today/O had/O to/O do/O with/O the/O presence/O of/O the/O police/O ./O 
It/O 's/O well/O known/O that/O the/O presence/O of/O uniformed/O officers/O tend/O to/O incite/O situations/O ./O 
And/O we/O 'd/O like/O to/O know/O --/O We/O 'd/O like/O --/O we/O 'd/O like/O to/O have/O your/O assurance/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O the/O police/O will/O not/O be/O called/O on/O the/O campus/O again/O --/O JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O -/O CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O --/O for/O just/O this/O reason/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O If/O you/O will/O give/O me/O assurance/O that/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O care/O --/O you/O can/O picket/O all/O you/O want/O to/O ./O 
But/O if/O you/O prevent/O people/O from/O going/O about/O their/O appointed/O tasks/O and/O do/O not/O allow/O them/O to/O do/O this/O ,/O and/O ,/O after/O I/O patiently/O waited/O for/O several/O hours/O --/O and/O do/O n't/O think/O this/O is/O n't/O going/O to/O ,/O going/O to/O ,/O have/O some/O backlash/O ,/O eh/O --/O you/O were/O --/O I/O --/O the/O --/O the/O ,/O uh/O ,/O picketers/O were/O requested/O to/O vacate/O the/O doorways/O ,/O and/O were/O ,/O I/O am/O told/O ,/O informed/O that/O they/O could/O go/O to/O a/O form/O of/O open/O picketing/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Why/O are/O there/O police/O here/O today/O ,/O right/O now/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O To/O protect/O the/O lives/O ,/O the/O property/O of/O yours/O and/O mine/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O My/O second/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Mis/O --/O Mr./O Turner/PERSON still/O has/O the/O mic/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O My/O second/O question/O has/O to/O do/O with/O ROTC/O ./O 
More/O than/O a/O year/O ago/O ,/O the/O arts/O and/O science/O --/O there/O was/O a/O committee/O of/O the/O Division/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O composed/O of/O faculty/O and/O students/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O ,/O which/O turned/O a/O report/O in/O which/O favored/O the/O position/O that/O no/O credit/O should/O be/O given/O for/O ROTC/O work/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O --/O At/O that/O time/O ,/O an/O all-university/O counc/O --/O committee/O was/O appointed/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O by/O ,/O by/O yourself/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Pardon/O ?/O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O At/O that/O time/O about/O a/O year/O ago/O ,/O when/O that/O report/O came/O in/O --/O JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Yes/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O --/O an/O all-university/O committee/O was/O appointed/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O And/O I/O have/O it/O that/O that/O committee/O has/O turned/O in/O a/O report/O to/O you/O ./O 
All/O right/O --/O that/O you/O have/O access/O to/O the/O findings/O of/O that/O committee/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Which/O is/O true/O ./O 
And/O a/O ,/O a/O ,/O uh/O ,/O that/O report/O has/O gone/O to/O the/O faculty/O council/O for/O its/O consideration/O and/O recommendation/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O is/O it/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O The/O ,/O uh/O ,/O recommendation/O was/O that/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O the/O details/O ./O 
But/O what/O you/O want/O to/O know/O is/O did/O they/O recom/O --/O did/O they/O recommend/O the/O abolition/O of/O ROTC/O or/O not/O ?/O 
And/O the/O answer/O is/O they/O did/O not/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O What/O about/O credit/O for/O ROTC/O credit/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O Mr./O Turner/PERSON ,/O can/O I/O speak/O to/O one/O point/O ?/O 
Because/O the/O arts/O and/O science/O report/O a/O year/O ago/O did/O not/O say/O no/O credit/O for/O ROTC/O ./O 
What/O it/O did/O was/O to/O make/O a/O recommendation/O to/O the/O faculty/O of/O the/O College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION that/O work/O in/O ROTC/O should/O not/O count/O within/O that/O portion/O of/O the/O student/O 's/O total/O program/O that/O must/O be/O taken/O within/O the/O College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O thus/O placed/O it/O in/O the/O same/O category/O as/O some/O of/O the/O other/O courses/O in/O professional/O schools/O ,/O uh/O ,/O that/O it/O could/O be/O taken/O ,/O but/O within/O the/O maximum/O allowed/O by/O the/O College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION to/O that/O point/O ./O 
It/O did/O not/O propose/O any/O immediate/O ending/O of/O credit/O ./O 
It/O had/O some/O long/O run/O proposals/O about/O ROTC/O ,/O uh/O ,/O which/O were/O to/O be/O phased/O over/O a/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
It/O was/O sent/O to/O an/O all-university/O committee/O ,/O because/O ROTC/ORGANIZATION is/O relevant/O not/O only/O to/O the/O faculty/O of/O the/O college/O and/O the/O students/O within/O the/O college/O ,/O but/O to/O all/O other/O students/O within/O the/O various/O divisions/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O I/O have/O one/O last/O quick/O question/O ,/O then/O I/O 'll/O release/O the/O mic/O ./O 
I/O 'd/O like/O to/O know/O if/O all/O the/O IU/O books/O are/O open/O to/O public/O ,/O and/O --/O including/O sources/O and/O uses/O of/O funds/O ./O 
And/O if/O not/O ,/O why/O not/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Well/O ,/O the/O IU/O foundation/O funds/O ,/O there/O are/O some/O of/O them/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O ,/O I/O 'm/O trying/O to/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O Trying/O to/O find/O out/O the/O answer/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O There/O --/O there/O is/O ,/O uh/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O ,/O uh/O ,/O a/O public/O accounting/O of/O all/O university/O use/O of/O funds/O made/O to/O the/O state/O of/O Indiana/LOCATION ./O 
And/O those/O become/O public/O documents/O ,/O and/O therefore/O ,/O are/O open/O ./O 
CHUCK/PERSON TURNER/PERSON :/O What/O about/O the/O foundation/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O I/O recognize/O the/O gentleman/O on/O the/O stage/O here/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O about/O foundation/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O the/O foundation/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O The/O foundation/O is/O honored/O annually/O by/O a/O firm/O from/O outside/O the/O institution/O ./O 
And/O the/O report/O of/O that/O audit/O is/O available/O in/O the/O foundation/O office/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O People/O ,/O I/O 'm/O representing/O Veterans/O for/O Peace/O and/O certain/O students/O at/O the/O law/O school/O ./O 
The/O --/O these/O are/O not/O ordinary/O times/O ./O 
This/O has/O not/O been/O an/O ordinary/O week/O ./O 
And/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O ordinary/O responses/O from/O the/O administration/O are/O appropriate/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O the/O situation/O which/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION finds/O itself/O in/O today/O demands/O an/O extraordinary/O response/O ./O 
I/O may/O turn/O some/O of/O you/O off/O but/O I/O want/O to/O say/O very/O clearly/O that/O I/O do/O not/O support/O closed/O picket/O lines/O ./O 
But/O ,/O if/O those/O lines/O were/O not/O closed/O this/O morning/O ,/O we/O would/O not/O be/O here/O today/O ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O Once/O again/O ,/O the/O audience/O is/O rising/O to/O its/O feet/O ,/O showing/O its/O solidarity/O ,/O at/O least/O on/O this/O point/O ,/O the/O emphasis/O being/O that/O student/O demands/O are/O only/O met/O by/O confrontation/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Now/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O many/O of/O you/O read/O The/O Daily/O Student/O this/O morning/O ,/O but/O I/O had/O a/O long/O essay/O in/O ,/O which/O was/O ,/O which/O was/O titled/O at/O the/O top/O ,/O \/O ``/O Do/O n't/O Shut/O Down/O the/O University/O ./O 
\/O ''/O If/O any/O of/O you/O --/O please/O ./O 
If/O any/O of/O you/O read/O further/O than/O the/O title/O ,/O you/O would/O see/O that/O the/O important/O part/O of/O that/O recommendation/O of/O that/O essay/O was/O the/O recommendation/O ,/O not/O the/O title/O ./O 
My/O recommendation/O was/O basically/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION plan/O ,/O which/O I/O 'll/O --/O let/O me/O explain/O in/O just/O a/O second/O ./O 
It/O was/O given/O to/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ,/O a/O personal/O copy/O yesterday/O ,/O and/O to/O Dean/PERSON Harvey/PERSON ,/O a/O personal/O copy/O yesterday/O ./O 
And/O all/O of/O you/O who/O read/O The/O Student/O this/O morning/O had/O an/O opportunity/O to/O see/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O ,/O because/O of/O my/O deep/O ingrained/O ,/O civil/O libertarian/O principles/O ,/O having/O lived/O in/O the/O south/O for/O many/O years/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O believe/O in/O unbridled/O majority/O rule/O ./O 
I/O do/O believe/O in/O preservation/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O minority/O ./O 
And/O therefore/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O the/O university/O should/O be/O closed/O down/O for/O everyone/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O it/O should/O --/O it/O should/O continue/O in/O existence/O ,/O business/O as/O usual/O ,/O for/O those/O who/O want/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
Wait/O 'll/O --/O wait/O 'll/O I/O finish/O ./O 
But/O just/O saying/O ,/O as/O the/O administration/O has/O made/O a/O pass/O at/O so/O far/O ,/O that/O they/O --/O that/O they/O will/O attempt/O to/O protect/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O do/O n't/O agree/O is/O not/O enough/O ./O 
I/O understand/O completely/O that/O the/O uni/O --/O that/O university/O administration/O can/O not/O order/O the/O faculty/O to/O do/O anything/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O n't/O have/O it/O any/O other/O way/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O they/O can/O clearly/O make/O their/O feelings/O known/O that/O they/O agree/O with/O the/O recommendation/O to/O each/O individual/O school/O ,/O to/O each/O individual/O school/O to/O handle/O any/O way/O they/O see/O fit/O to/O allow/O those/O of/O us/O who/O want/O to/O go/O out/O in/O the/O community/O ,/O who/O want/O to/O go/O to/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O who/O want/O to/O speak/O ,/O write/O ,/O lobby/O in/O our/O own/O way/O ,/O or/O to/O do/O --/O do/O more/O constructive/O things/O during/O the/O next/O three/O weeks/O than/O take/O exams/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
And/O it/O should/O be/O a/O clear/O recommendation/O from/O both/O the/O president/O and/O the/O chancellor/O that/O their/O --/O that/O classes/O will/O be/O waived/O ,/O exams/O will/O be/O waived/O ,/O and/O credit/O will/O be/O given/O automatically/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O in/O the/O productivity/O of/O interfering/O with/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O ,/O sometimes/O for/O very/O sound/O pragmatic/O reasons/O ,/O are/O here/O at/O great/O personal/O expense/O ,/O either/O to/O themselves/O or/O to/O others/O ./O 
I/O think/O they/O should/O be/O able/O to/O continue/O to/O go/O to/O class/O and/O continue/O to/O take/O exams/O ./O 
And/O --/O but/O I/O think/O that/O the/O university/O has/O an/O obligation/O ,/O taken/O within/O the/O broadest/O possible/O context/O of/O what/O 's/O been/O going/O on/O in/O the/O country/O in/O the/O last/O 10/O days/O ,/O to/O see/O this/O step/O as/O an/O extraordinary/O step/O ,/O perhaps/O ,/O for/O this/O state/O and/O this/O administration/O ,/O but/O as/O a/O very/O minor/O step/O taken/O when/O we/O consider/O the/O alternative/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O And/O I/O think/O they/O have/O an/O obligation/O to/O say/O ,/O yes/O ,/O while/O I/O would/O not/O ordinarily/O do/O so/O ,/O these/O are/O extraordinary/O times/O ,/O and/O I/O recommend/O to/O the/O --/O to/O the/O other/O school/O leaders/O that/O they/O do/O --/O that/O they/O do/O exactly/O this/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O ,/O I/O have/O the/O highest/O regard/O for/O this/O man/O from/O working/O with/O him/O ./O 
He/O spent/O 12/O years/O in/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Force/ORGANIZATION ,/O resigned/O his/O commission/O last/O year/O ,/O because/O it/O was/O ethically/O unjustifiable/O ./O 
And/O he/O 's/O president/O of/O the/O student/O body/O of/O the/O law/O class/O ./O 
And/O he/O 's/O a/O member/O with/O me/O of/O the/O Veterans/O for/O Peace/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
We/O 've/O got/O a/O reply/O from/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON to/O Mr./O Boyle/PERSON ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Well/O ,/O can/O I/O reply/O ?/O 
Again/O ,/O I/O thought/O I/O --/O excuse/O me/O ./O 
I/O thought/O I/O had/O already/O said/O that/O in/O my/O judgment/O --/O --/O the/O recommendation/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Come/O on/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O --/O that/O I/O personally/O favor/O the/O recommendation/O made/O by/O the/O faculty/O council/O yesterday/O ,/O which/O went/O straight/O in/O the/O direction/O which/O is/O indicated/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O by/O this/O last/O part/O of/O the/O comments/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O received/O the/O letter/O as/O yet/O ./O 
But/O I/O 've/O been/O a/O little/O busy/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Just/O ,/O there/O 's/O a/O brief/O announcement/O just/O make/O about/O the/O students/O who/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O am/O Chris/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Lohman/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
from/O the/O English/O department/O ,/O and/O Tom/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Shornhorse/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
and/O Shelley/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Geller/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
and/O Peter/PERSON Lintenbaum/PERSON and/O I/O just/O came/O from/O the/O jail/O ./O 
The/O eight/O people/O who/O were/O arrested/O are/O out/O ./O 
They/O --/O They/O have/O been/O arraigned/O on/O ,/O uh/O ,/O uh/O ,/O $/O 50/O bond/O --/O they/O 've/O been/O released/O on/O $/O 50/O bail/O apiece/O ./O 
That/O 's/O $/O 400/O ./O 
The/O bail/O money/O was/O raised/O by/O the/O faculty/O ./O 
And/O ,/O uh/O --/O But/O there/O is/O one/O very/O important/O point/O about/O this/O ./O 
And/O it/O 's/O only/O because/O of/O the/O crowded/O conditions/O that/O Tom/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Shornhorse/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
is/O n't/O talking/O to/O you/O ./O 
We/O did/O n't/O all/O want/O to/O march/O down/O here/O ./O 
Tom/PERSON is/O very/O concerned/O --/O Tom/PERSON represents/O the/O eight/O students/O in/O court/O from/O now/O on/O ./O 
And/O Tom/PERSON is/O very/O much/O concerned/O that/O you/O all/O know/O that/O the/O judge/O made/O a/O particular/O effort/O ,/O and/O we/O mean/O this/O quite/O seriously/O ,/O to/O set/O the/O bonds/O as/O low/O as/O possible/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O they/O could/O have/O been/O at/O $/O 500/O apiece/O ,/O with/O the/O idea/O that/O there/O is/O going/O to/O be/O some/O reciprocation/O to/O this/O from/O our/O part/O --/O that/O ,/O in/O other/O words/O ,/O the/O implication/O was/O quite/O clear/O that/O if/O anybody/O 's/O going/O to/O be/O busted/O tonight/O ,/O it/O 's/O not/O going/O to/O be/O $/O 50/O ./O 
It/O 's/O going/O to/O be/O $/O 500/O apiece/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O We/O all/O know/O that/O ./O 
But/O all/O I/O can/O say/O is/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O we/O can/O raise/O $/O 500/O apiece/O for/O a/O number/O of/O students/O from/O now/O ./O 
So/O I/O hope/O you/O all/O keep/O this/O in/O mind/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Uh/O ,/O we/O counted/O the/O money/O back/O stage/O ./O 
And/O we/O were/O able/O to/O collect/O $/O 446.18/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O since/O those/O brothers/O and/O sisters/O have/O been/O bailed/O out/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O it/O would/O be/O beneficial/O for/O us/O to/O put/O this/O into/O a/O permanent/O fund/O ,/O because/O uh/O ,/O this/O little/O idea/O 's/O been/O running/O in/O my/O head/O that/O it/O 's/O going/O to/O be/O used/O again/O ./O 
And/O while/O I/O --/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O make/O one/O more/O announcement/O about/O the/O teach/O in/O tonight/O ./O 
7:00/O PM/O right/O here/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O in/O the/O auditorium/O --/O and/O the/O main/O speakers/O will/O be/O Professor/O Stan/PERSON on/O containment/O in/O Vietnam/LOCATION ,/O Professor/O Edward/PERSON Sherman/PERSON on/O the/O American/O servicemen/O and/O Indo-Chinese/O war/O ,/O Professor/O Julius/PERSON ,/O Vietnam/LOCATION and/O political/O dissent/O ;/O Professor/O George/PERSON -LSB-/O ?/O 
Jergens/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
domestic/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
menace/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
of/O Vietnam/LOCATION --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
--/O and/O Keith/PERSON Parker/PERSON ,/O the/O Black/O Panthers/O and/O political/O repression/O ./O 
There/O 'll/O be/O workshops/O to/O follow/O ./O 
And/O then/O there/O 'll/O be/O a/O wrap/O up/O session/O in/O the/O auditorium/O after/O the/O workshops/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O I/O promised/O the/O gentleman/O who/O asked/O the/O first/O question/O that/O he/O would/O be/O recognized/O later/O ./O 
And/O I/O do/O so/O now/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O There/O 's/O no/O microphone/O anywhere/O near/O here/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Just/O keep/O shouting/O ./O 
We/O 'll/O repeat/O your/O question/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
things/O have/O come/O to/O mind/O today/O ./O 
with/O a/O family/O about/O to/O graduate/O next/O month/O ./O 
have/O to/O work/O while/O going/O to/O school/O ./O 
Whether/O you/O have/O or/O not/O is/O immaterial/O ./O 
I/O paid/O for/O my/O education/O ,/O and/O I/O intend/O to/O get/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O People/O in/O Vietnam/LOCATION died/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O And/O there/O are/O many/O people/O here/O who/O would/O like/O to/O get/O that/O same/O education/O ,/O whether/O they/O paid/O for/O it/O ,/O did/O n't/O pay/O for/O it/O ,/O or/O anything/O else/O immaterial/O ./O 
But/O they/O want/O to/O go/O to/O class/O ./O 
I/O could/O reference/O 9,800/O and/O some/O odd/O students/O said/O that/O they/O did/O not/O want/O to/O go/O to/O class/O for/O four/O days/O ./O 
7,000/O some/O odd/O said/O that/O they/O did/O want/O to/O go/O to/O class/O ./O 
12,000/O abstained/O ./O 
Why/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Silent/O majority/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O speaker/O finish/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O minority/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Want/O to/O play/O majority/O ?/O 
12/O plus/O seven/O makes/O 19/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O let/O the/O speaker/O finish/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O We/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O One/O thing/O that/O must/O be/O recognized/O is/O that/O every/O individual/O student/O has/O an/O individual/O contract/O with/O the/O university/O that/O guarantees/O ,/O by/O civil/O law/O ,/O ./O 
justification/O ,/O according/O to/O Attorney/O General/O last/O year/O ./O 
As/O such/O ,/O each/O and/O every/O demonstrator/O to/O a/O court/O order/O violation/O to/O each/O and/O every/O student/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Now/O ,/O we/O all/O ./O 
We/O all/O with/O what/O we/O 're/O here/O for/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O re/O --/O please/O reach/O --/O please/O reach/O the/O point/O of/O your/O question/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O All/O right/O ./O 
Just/O --/O The/O ,/O the/O ,/O uh/O ,/O the/O ,/O the/O --/O just/O a/O minute/O ,/O please/O ./O 
The/O issue/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O who/O want/O to/O go/O to/O class/O have/O been/O raised/O by/O several/O speakers/O ,/O have/O been/O responded/O to/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O particular/O statement/O will/O ,/O needs/O more/O comments/O ./O 
We/O will/O now/O recognize/O other/O questions/O ./O 
The/O gentleman/O right/O there/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O ask/O President/O Sutton/PERSON --/O you/O mentioned/O a/O while/O ago/O a/O possible/O backlash/O going/O on/O down/O here/O ./O 
Are/O you/O more/O concerned/O ,/O is/O the/O administration/O more/O concerned/O with/O our/O image/O or/O with/O what/O the/O people/O feel/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O I/O 'm/O not/O an/O expert/O on/O what/O the/O people/O feel/O ./O 
Because/O I/O know/O they/O feel/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Can/O we/O let/O President/O Sutton/PERSON finish/O the/O answer/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Because/O I/O know/O they/O feel/O many/O things/O ./O 
But/O if/O your/O question/O is/O to/O me/O ,/O do/O I/O respect/O people/O 's/O feelings/O and/O thereby/O --/O oh/O ,/O let/O me/O see/O how/O to/O put/O that/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O afraid/O --/O afraid/O of/O the/O backlash/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Ike/PERSON --/O or/O ,/O let/O --/O with/O the/O microphone/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O This/O ,/O this/O whole/O topic/O keeps/O coming/O back/O up/O about/O the/O vote/O and/O what/O it/O meant/O ,/O or/O the/O referendum/O ./O 
And/O I/O still/O do/O n't/O think/O the/O question/O was/O really/O answered/O a/O moment/O ago/O ,/O when/O ,/O uh/O ,/O you/O said/O there/O would/O be/O recommendations/O about/O students/O who/O had/O voted/O to/O dissent/O ,/O or/O voted/O to/O strike/O ./O 
You/O said/O there/O would/O be/O recommendations/O made/O ./O 
And/O there/O ,/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O was/O the/O statement/O by/O the/O law/O professor/O ,/O who/O said/O these/O are/O extraordinary/O times/O ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O they/O are/O ,/O and/O you/O can/O guarantee/O people/O 's/O rights/O to/O go/O to/O class/O ,/O why/O can/O not/O you/O guarantee/O the/O rights/O of/O those/O people/O who/O wish/O to/O dissent/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Now/O ,/O this/O is/O really/O a/O Bloomington/LOCATION campus/O matter/O ./O 
Why/O ,/O he/O 'll/O --/O he/O 's/O willing/O to/O talk/O too/O ,/O but/O I/O want/O to/O try/O to/O answer/O this/O as/O directly/O as/O I/O can/O answer/O it/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O there/O at/O the/O council/O discussion/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O not/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Why/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Because/O it/O 's/O the/O Bloomington/LOCATION faculty/O council/O ,/O and/O I/O preside/O ,/O and/O he/O 's/O not/O a/O member/O ./O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O Um/O ,/O my/O --/O JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O May/O I/O answer/O that/O question/O ?/O 
I/O think/O ,/O basically/O ,/O what/O I/O 've/O tried/O to/O get/O across/O before/O is/O the/O administration/O is/O not/O authorized/O to/O make/O these/O decisions/O by/O itself/O ./O 
What/O happened/O was/O the/O council/O recommended/O this/O kind/O of/O thing/O to/O ,/O to/O the/O faculty/O as/O a/O whole/O ./O 
What/O is/O happening/O is/O that/O ,/O in/O division/O after/O division/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O get/O reports/O ,/O they/O are/O taking/O it/O up/O ./O 
As/O I/O said/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O arts/O ,/O Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION already/O has/O ,/O has/O tried/O to/O deal/O with/O this/O through/O its/O elected/O policy/O committee/O ./O 
And/O the/O law/O school/O is/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O know/O the/O business/O school/O is/O planning/O to/O meet/O ./O 
But/O I/O ca/O n't/O reach/O in/O and/O tell/O them/O what/O they/O must/O do/O ./O 
I/O can/O do/O what/O I/O said/O earlier/O and/O express/O a/O sentiment/O of/O sympathy/O for/O the/O position/O ./O 
But/O they/O 're/O going/O to/O have/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Excuse/O me/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O like/O to/O also/O ask/O ,/O in/O connection/O with/O that/O ,/O is/O this/O a/O democratic/O institution/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O No/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O And/O if/O it/O is/O so-called/O ,/O then/O how/O can/O those/O two/O ideas/O be/O reconciled/O ?/O 
Is/O it/O a/O corporate/O interest/O or/O institution/O ?/O 
And/O do/O you/O reconcile/O corporate/O interests/O with/O democratic/O ideals/O and/O principles/O ?/O 
Or/O are/O they/O separate/O ?/O 
There/O was/O a/O vote/O and/O a/O recom/O --/O referendum/O taken/O here/O ./O 
And/O the/O majority/O of/O the/O students/O voted/O ./O 
That/O 's/O ,/O that/O 's/O democratic/O ./O 
I/O always/O thought/O it/O was/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Mr./O Pratter/PERSON wants/O to/O speak/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O This/O is/O a/O very/O difficult/O and/O profound/O question/O that/O 's/O raised/O ./O 
Democracy/O is/O not/O so/O simple/O that/O its/O dimensions/O are/O self-evident/O ./O 
The/O question/O about/O the/O majority/O vote/O is/O a/O question/O of/O what/O belongs/O on/O the/O agenda/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O ,/O by/O majority/O vote/O ,/O to/O strip/O the/O people/O of/O their/O constitutional/O rights/O ?/O 
The/O whole/O point/O of/O a/O democracy/O is/O that/O it/O has/O limits/O ./O 
The/O whole/O point/O of/O a/O democracy/O is/O there/O are/O constitutional/O protections/O for/O certain/O minorities/O ./O 
I/O --/O as/O an/O ,/O as/O educated/O people/O ,/O as/O people/O who/O are/O attempting/O to/O understand/O our/O society/O ,/O we/O must/O begin/O to/O understand/O what/O we/O mean/O by/O democracy/O in/O a/O more/O complicated/O way/O than/O all/O questions/O are/O resolved/O ./O 
So/O there/O are/O issues/O as/O to/O what/O items/O can/O be/O put/O on/O the/O agenda/O ./O 
The/O answer/O 's/O along/O the/O line/O of/O every/O question/O has/O been/O that/O we/O are/O trying/O to/O walk/O a/O path/O ./O 
We/O are/O trying/O to/O develop/O programs/O that/O do/O protect/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O students/O who/O have/O dissented/O ,/O the/O rights/O of/O the/O students/O who/O feel/O they/O 're/O incapable/O of/O taking/O exams/O ./O 
I/O just/O came/O from/O a/O law/O school/O meeting/O where/O we/O have/O special/O constraints/O on/O how/O much/O we/O can/O relieve/O our/O students/O ./O 
And/O we/O are/O struggling/O with/O this/O problem/O ./O 
I/O know/O that/O Arts/O and/O Science/O ,/O we/O can/O at/O least/O agree/O that/O we/O can/O not/O take/O action/O when/O the/O campus/O is/O as/O seriously/O split/O and/O the/O student/O vote/O by/O a/O mere/O majority/O vote/O principle/O ./O 
We/O can/O adjust/O matters/O in/O terms/O of/O grades/O and/O credits/O ,/O as/O been/O suggested/O ,/O that/O would/O do/O justice/O to/O both/O ./O 
That/O 's/O the/O point/O of/O this/O meeting/O ./O 
We/O have/O made/O an/O op/O --/O an/O impact/O on/O how/O many/O of/O the/O ,/O how/O many/O of/O the/O students/O feel/O strongly/O that/O this/O university/O can/O not/O merely/O continue/O ./O 
We/O have/O shown/O ./O 
We/O have/O done/O things/O ./O 
And/O we/O can/O do/O it/O without/O creating/O bitterness/O in/O those/O who/O perhaps/O do/O n't/O feel/O ,/O at/O ,/O on/O these/O issues/O ,/O their/O ,/O their/O ,/O uh/O ,/O rights/O can/O be/O compromised/O by/O the/O majority/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Mr./O Pratter/PERSON ,/O uh/O --/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ,/O uh/O ,/O like/O to/O ask/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O as/O a/O moderator/O ,/O you/O know/O why/O you/O 're/O running/O all/O this/O ./O 
Because/O the/O moderator/O should/O be/O sitting/O here/O ,/O pointing/O out/O people/O to/O ask/O questions/O ,/O and/O not/O running/O all/O these/O comments/O ./O 
And/O then/O ,/O I/O have/O one/O more/O --/O I/O have/O one/O more/O question/O to/O ask/O myself/O ./O 
It/O 's/O in/O two/O parts/O ./O 
Although/O President/O Sutton/PERSON has/O assumed/O responsibility/O for/O ,/O for/O ,/O uh/O ,/O asking/O for/O the/O police/O to/O come/O ,/O who/O was/O the/O person/O that/O called/O the/O police/O ?/O 
Who/O was/O this/O person/O ?/O 
And/O second/O of/O all/O ,/O why/O are/O we/O sitting/O up/O here/O on/O this/O stage/O with/O ,/O uh/O ,/O various/O members/O of/O that/O same/O police/O force/O behind/O us/O ,/O armed/O to/O the/O gills/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Would/O you/O want/O to/O handle/O that/O one/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O guts/O want/O to/O waste/O time/O ,/O that/O 's/O what/O they/O 're/O doing/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Let/O 's/O say/O I/O called/O them/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O J/O --/O just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Ah/O ,/O I/O --/O I/O was/O carried/O away/O ./O 
I/O apologize/O ./O 
I/O did/O it/O in/O the/O best/O interest/O of/O trying/O to/O reach/O understanding/O ./O 
To/O compensate/O for/O ,/O by/O default/O ,/O I/O 'll/O ask/O my/O moderator/O if/O he/O wants/O equal/O time/O ./O 
Not/O --/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Answer/O them/O why/O there/O are/O pigs/O back/O there/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
You/O wan/O na/O answer/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O That/O question/O was/O asked/O of/O me/O once/O before/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O me/O tell/O you/O this/O ./O 
And/O I/O know/O --/O I/O know/O that/O you/O 're/O --/O anything/O I/O say/O about/O this/O ,/O however/O reasonable/O ,/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O ,/O is/O going/O to/O meet/O with/O some/O kind/O of/O hostility/O response/O on/O the/O part/O of/O you/O automatically/O ./O 
The/O Safety/ORGANIZATION Division/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION is/O trained/O --/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
KEITH/PERSON PARKER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
Just/O --/O JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O ,/O if/O you/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O hear/O the/O answer/O ,/O just/O forget/O it/O ./O 
But/O --/O are/O trained/O and/O ,/O and/O instructed/O to/O protect/O the/O lives/O --/O all/O right/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Hey/O ,/O let/O 's/O --/O let/O 's/O let/O the/O man/O finish/O at/O least/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O you/O do/O n't/O have/O to/O like/O what/O he/O says/O ./O 
But/O let/O him/O get/O it/O out/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
I/O --/O I/O ,/O I/O know/O in/O advance/O that/O many/O of/O you/O are/O not/O going/O to/O like/O what/O I/O say/O ./O 
But/O they/O are/O trained/O and/O advised/O and/O instructed/O to/O be/O as/O sensitive/O and/O as/O careful/O in/O the/O protection/O of/O your/O lives/O as/O they/O can/O be/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O have/O you/O done/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Pardon/O me/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O The/O Harvard/ORGANIZATION report/O !/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O The/O Harvard/ORGANIZATION report/O is/O being/O implemented/O as/O rapidly/O as/O it/O can/O be/O implemented/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Take/O the/O guns/O away/O from/O them/O !/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O I/O 'll/O --/O now/O ,/O here/O again/O ./O 
You/O wanted/O to/O hear/O it/O like/O it/O is/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ,/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O plan/O to/O recommend/O that/O the/O guns/O be/O removed/O from/O the/O police/O force/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Let/O 's/O let/O Ike/PERSON speak/O ./O 
Ike/PERSON ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O You/O asked/O me/O the/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O answered/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Um/O ,/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O ask/O a/O question/O pertaining/O to/O the/O so-called/O ,/O quote/O unquote/O ,/O neutrality/O of/O this/O university/O ./O 
Um/O ,/O I/O 'm/O sure/O President/O Sutton/PERSON is/O aware/O ,/O since/O he/O was/O there/O for/O three/O years/O ,/O of/O what/O this/O unity/O --/O this/O university/O does/O in/O the/O Thailand/LOCATION project/O ./O 
And/O I/O 'd/O like/O to/O throw/O a/O few/O facts/O out/O about/O that/O ./O 
Thailand/LOCATION has/O not/O had/O a/O free/O election/O in/O 28/O years/O ./O 
This/O university/O has/O spent/O $/O 1.3/O million/O to/O send/O people/O over/O to/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O to/O train/O people/O over/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O the/O question/O of/O ROTC/O is/O concerned/O ,/O if/O you/O check/O out/O the/O quotes/O of/O military/O leaders/O of/O this/O country/O ,/O they/O say/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION government/O could/O not/O wage/O war/O ,/O or/O whatever/O they/O call/O it/O ,/O in/O overseas/O countries/O if/O it/O was/O n't/O for/O the/O ROTC/O program/O ./O 
70/O %/O of/O the/O officers/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Army/LOCATION in/O Vietnam/LOCATION are/O ROTC/O graduates/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O you/O people/O are/O wrapped/O up/O in/O a/O civil/O liberties/O thing/O about/O ROTC/O ,/O dig/O it/O ./O 
Right/O on/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O the/O ,/O the/O civil/O liberties/O of/O the/O Vietnamese/O people/O and/O the/O Cambodian/O people/O to/O live/O without/O being/O napalmed/O on/O by/O American/O imperialists/O is/O more/O important/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
This/O gentleman/O right/O here/O ,/O please/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Do/O you/O want/O to/O respond/O ?/O 
It/O 's/O all/O right/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Did/O you/O ask/O me/O a/O question/O about/O Thailand/LOCATION ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O All/O right/O ./O 
I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
The/O contract/O between/O the/O university/O and/O Thailand/LOCATION during/O the/O period/O that/O I/O was/O there/O and/O subsequent/O to/O my/O return/O to/O this/O country/O is/O available/O ./O 
And/O you/O may/O read/O it/O ./O 
Our/O prop/O ,/O pur/O ,/O purpose/O there/O was/O twofold/O ./O 
One/O ,/O the/O School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Education/ORGANIZATION was/O developing/O a/O college/O of/O education/O to/O train/O teachers/O for/O the/O children/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION throughout/O the/O country/O and/O open/O new/O schools/O ./O 
And/O that/O ,/O you/O can/O see/O in/O the/O contract/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O --/O it/O --/O if/O they/O get/O educated/O at/O a/O --/O I/O --/O well/O ,/O you/O ./O 
All/O right/O ,/O it/O 's/O propaganda/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Please/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O But/O I/O was/O asked/O what/O we/O were/O doing/O ./O 
And/O you/O --/O if/O you/O want/O me/O to/O answer/O ,/O I/O will/O complete/O the/O answer/O ,/O and/O then/O again/O ,/O eh/O ,/O do/O your/O own/O thing/O ./O 
The/O other/O ,/O the/O other/O part/O --/O all/O right/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Keep/O talking/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O ,/O I/O 'm/O trying/O to/O ./O 
-LSB-/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O ?/O -RSB-/O 
You/O 've/O finished/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Uh/O ,/O the/O other/O part/O of/O the/O contract/O was/O to/O train/O young/O administrators/O to/O go/O out/O into/O the/O countryside/O of/O ha/O ,/O Thailand/LOCATION ./O 
Much/O ,/O much/O --/O it/O 's/O almost/O all/O rural/O ,/O almost/O all/O agrarian/O --/O and/O provide/O better/O service/O to/O --/O and/O these/O are/O all/O civilians/O --/O better/O service/O to/O the/O peasants/O and/O the/O people/O of/O the/O ,/O of/O Thailand/LOCATION itself/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O ./O 
I/O recognize/O the/O gentleman/O right/O in/O front/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Now/O ,/O I/O might/O --/O now/O ,/O let/O me/O --/O oh/O ,/O no/O ,/O I/O have/O n't/O finished/O the/O --/O I/O have/O n't/O finished/O the/O answer/O ,/O because/O I/O want/O to/O tell/O you/O all/O I/O know/O about/O it/O as/O briefly/O as/O I/O can/O ./O 
How/O do/O you/O --/O I/O mean/O ,/O was/O the/O question/O a/O serious/O one/O or/O not/O ?/O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Currently/O ,/O Indiana/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION is/O in/O a/O con/O --/O consortium/O with/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Wisconsin/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Michigan/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O ah/O ,/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Minnesota/ORGANIZATION ,/O ah/O ,/O Indiana/LOCATION --/O yes/O ,/O they/O 're/O all/O big/O 10/O schools/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O well/O ,/O I/O 'm/O --/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O all/O of/O them/O offhand/O ./O 
But/O they/O are/O being/O financed/O to/O help/O --/O these/O are/O all/O professors/O of/O economics/O ,/O statistics/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ,/O agricultural/O economics/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
This/O contract/O is/O financed/O by/O the/O Ford/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O purposes/O of/O developing/O something/O known/O as/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Development/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O ,/O the/O purpose/O of/O that/O is/O described/O by/O the/O name/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O kind/O of/O government/O do/O they/O have/O in/O Thailand/LOCATION ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O They/O have/O the/O kind/O of/O government/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O there/O ,/O that/O had/O more/O school/O teachers/O than/O it/O had/O soldiers/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O The/O gentleman/O right/O in/O front/O here/O ./O 
Quiet/O ,/O please/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O come/O out/O and/O answer/O this/O man/O ./O 
And/O last/O year/O ,/O during/O the/O boycott/O ,/O -LSB-/O ?/O 
Snyder/PERSON ?/O -RSB-/O 
came/O out/O and/O told/O us/O why/O we/O could/O n't/O vote/O ./O 
But/O you/O did/O not/O come/O out/O and/O meet/O us/O until/O there/O was/O violence/O ./O 
You/O pat/O us/O on/O the/O back/O for/O being/O peaceful/O ,/O but/O you/O do/O n't/O say/O anything/O until/O there/O 's/O violence/O ./O 
Why/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Again/O ,/O for/O some/O of/O you/O ,/O this/O answer/O will/O not/O be/O satisfactory/O ./O 
But/O I/O will/O admit/O that/O I/O should/O have/O done/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O do/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Why/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Why/O ?/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Why/O ?/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O No/O ,/O I/O was/O not/O afraid/O ./O 
If/O I/O was/O afraid/O ,/O I/O 'm/O here/O --/O oh/O ,/O come/O on/O ./O 
Knock/O it/O off/O ./O 
If/O --/O If/O you/O want/O to/O just/O --/O I/O mean/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O to/O badger/O me/O ,/O uh/O ,/O we/O could/O go/O out/O ,/O and/O come/O out/O ,/O badger/O me/O ./O 
I/O thought/O we/O were/O trying/O to/O get/O questions/O answered/O ./O 
And/O I/O 'm/O answering/O the/O question/O ./O 
I/O made/O a/O mistake/O ./O 
That/O 's/O all/O ./O 
I/O am/O fallible/O ./O 
And/O I/O confess/O to/O it/O ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O The/O fallibility/O that/O ,/O uh/O ,/O President/O Sutton/PERSON admitted/O to/O was/O that/O he/O should/O have/O met/O with/O students/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O --/O uh/O --/O REPORTER/O :/O --/O when/O they/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Marty/PERSON ./O 
REPORTER/O :/O --/O asked/O why/O he/O did/O not/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O have/O a/O --/O I/O have/O a/O very/O brief/O question/O for/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O uh/O ,/O that/O this/O question/O can/O also/O be/O answered/O yes/O or/O no/O ./O 
And/O first/O of/O all/O ,/O uh/O ,/O it/O 's/O my/O understanding/O that/O ,/O also/O ,/O besides/O being/O chancellor/O ,/O that/O you/O are/O a/O faculty/O member/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O hope/O so/O ,/O because/O that/O 's/O all/O I/O 've/O got/O tenure/O as/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Well/O ,/O then/O ,/O would/O you/O respond/O --/O would/O you/O respond/O under/O the/O understanding/O that/O you/O are/O responding/O as/O a/O faculty/O member/O of/O this/O institution/O ,/O and/O not/O as/O its/O chancellor/O to/O a/O question/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/O :/O Depends/O on/O the/O question/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O 'll/O ask/O the/O question/O ./O 
You/O have/O heard/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION plane/O presented/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Do/O you/O understand/O it/O ?/O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O 'm/O not/O sure/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O 've/O --/O if/O you/O mean/O this/O statement/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O Yeah/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O 've/O heard/O it/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O OK/O ./O 
He/O heard/O it/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Uh/O ,/O then/O my/O question/O is/O --/O and/O I/O think/O it/O can/O be/O answered/O yes/O or/O no/O ./O 
As/O a/O faculty/O member/O of/O this/O t/O ,/O institution/O ,/O with/O the/O understanding/O that/O you/O are/O not/O responding/O as/O chancellor/O ,/O but/O as/O a/O faculty/O member/O ,/O would/O you/O endorse/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION plan/O ?/O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O We/O 're/O going/O to/O give/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON a/O few/O minutes/O to/O read/O it/O over/O ./O 
BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O No/O ,/O yeah/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O It/O 's/O in/O the/O student/O --/O BYRUM/PERSON CARTER/PERSON :/O I/O tell/O you/O ,/O I/O read/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O The/O brown/O ,/O right/O in/O front/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Yeah/O ./O 
DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O If/O it/O 's/O not/O for/O --/O HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Ask/O another/O question/O while/O Chancellor/O Carter/PERSON ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Could/O I/O --/O yeah/O ./O 
I/O would/O ,/O uh/O --/O All/O right/O ,/O now/O ,/O please/O --/O DALE/PERSON PRYWELLER/PERSON :/O Go/O ahead/O ,/O man/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Everybody/O ,/O all/O right/O ,/O everybody/O in/O this/O place/O is/O getting/O a/O little/O pissed/O ./O 
But/O could/O I/O have/O your/O attention/O for/O just/O a/O minute/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Everybody/O 's/O just/O a/O little/O bit/O tense/O ./O 
And/O my/O Greek/O blood/O is/O running/O a/O little/O hot/O too/O ./O 
And/O that/O does/O n't/O mean/O I/O 'm/O in/O a/O fraternity/O ./O 
That/O means/O my/O old/O man/O came/O over/O on/O the/O boat/O ./O 
All/O right/O ?/O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O 's/O quit/O throwing/O the/O bullshit/O around/O ,/O and/O quit/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O running/O around/O this/O little/O bush/O ,/O because/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O there/O 's/O an/O issue/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
And/O this/O issue/O comes/O up/O ./O 
And/O from/O this/O issue/O come/O a/O lot/O of/O little/O issues/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
And/O all/O these/O people/O get/O pissed/O about/O these/O little/O things/O ./O 
Like/O ,/O you/O watch/O CBS/ORGANIZATION ,/O you/O know/O ,/O and/O you/O see/O these/O construction/O guys/O getting/O all/O uptight/O ./O 
And/O some/O girl/O up/O here/O stands/O up/O ,/O and/O she/O 's/O getting/O uptight/O because/O she/O 's/O getting/O pushed/O around/O ./O 
But/O the/O issue/O is/O troops/O went/O into/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O 
The/O issue/O is/O people/O are/O being/O killed/O right/O now/O ./O 
That/O 's/O the/O issue/O ./O 
We/O 're/O expanding/O a/O war/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O 's/O get/O back/O to/O the/O issue/O ./O 
The/O issue/O is/O not/O students/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O diversion/O ./O 
That/O 's/O to/O make/O people/O in/O the/O back/O pissed/O at/O the/O people/O up/O in/O the/O front/O ./O 
That/O 's/O all/O it/O is/O ./O 
That/O 's/O a/O diversion/O ./O 
That/O 's/O bullshit/O ./O 
That/O 's/O politics/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O 's/O get/O down/O to/O an/O issue/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O there/O 's/O a/O lot/O of/O pissed/O people/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O all/O right/O ,/O Mr./O Sutton/PERSON you/O represent/O this/O university/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O said/O this/O before/O ./O 
OK/O ,/O there/O 's/O 9,000/O people/O in/O this/O university/O that/O are/O pissed/O enough/O to/O show/O up/O to/O the/O polls/O ./O 
And/O that/O does/O n't/O include/O your/O 12,000/O ./O 
40/O %/O of/O the/O people/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION did/O n't/O vote/O for/O the/O president/O ./O 
Big/O deal/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O You/O minutes/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Now/O ,/O wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Let/O me/O finish/O this/O out/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O 're/O responsible/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O there/O 's/O 9,000/O people/O that/O are/O pissed/O enough/O to/O say/O we/O want/O something/O done/O ./O 
And/O then/O there/O 's/O some/O other/O people/O that/O are/O pissed/O at/O us/O ,/O so/O they/O say/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O oh/O ,/O well/O --/O excuse/O me/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Could/O you/O to/O keep/O that/O down/O to/O a/O minimum/O ?/O 
Or/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O OK/O ,/O now/O ,/O wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Can/O I/O get/O this/O question/O ?/O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O --/O all/O right/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O I/O mean/O ,/O the/O figure/O of/O speech/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Right/O ./O 
OK/O ./O 
Um/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O Quiet/O !/O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O All/O right/O ./O 
This/O is/O for/O most/O people/O that/O are/O pissed/O at/O me/O in/O the/O back/O ./O 
Uh/O ,/O I/O can/O shove/O you/O in/O any/O picket/O line/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O want/O your/O help/O ./O 
And/O now/O ,/O I/O want/O Mr./O Sutton/PERSON 's/O help/O ./O 
And/O I/O want/O your/O help/O ./O 
What/O are/O you/O going/O to/O do/O with/O us/O ?/O 
There/O 's/O 9,000/O people/O ,/O if/O not/O more/O ./O 
What/O will/O you/O do/O --/O ,/O no/O we/O 're/O talking/O about/O our/O lives/O ,/O mister/O ,/O because/O people/O are/O going/O to/O graduate/O ,/O and/O they/O 're/O going/O to/O have/O to/O go/O over/O to/O Cambodia/LOCATION ./O 
What/O will/O you/O do/O to/O help/O us/O ?/O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Thank/O you/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Will/O you/O come/O to/O a/O teach/O in/O ?/O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O All/O right/O ./O 
Please/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Mr./O Sutton/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Sutton/PERSON ,/O whether/O you/O can/O --/O you/O can/O not/O get/O away/O from/O it/O ./O 
And/O whether/O you/O 're/O president/O of/O this/O university/O you/O 're/O not/O ,/O you/O 're/O a/O person/O ./O 
And/O this/O thing/O about/O ,/O that/O my/O job/O does/O n't/O enable/O me/O to/O feel/O and/O to/O act/O is/O a/O lot/O of/O bullshit/O ,/O man/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O It/O AUDIENCE/O :/O That/O 's/O a/O lot/O of/O bullshit/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O We/O are/O recognizing/O --/O AUDIENCE/O :/O What/O will/O you/O do/O ,/O as/O Mr./O S/O --/O I/O 'm/O asking/O --/O HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O If/O you/O recognize/O people/O as/O people/O ,/O will/O you/O give/O a/O chance/O to/O respond/O ?/O 
You/O 've/O made/O your/O point/O ./O 
You/O ,/O you/O --/O we/O know/O you/O 've/O made/O your/O point/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O that/O 's/O it/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Say/O what/O you/O feel/O as/O a/O human/O being/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O What/O I/O feel/O as/O a/O human/O being/O is/O this/O ./O 
And/O again/O ,/O I/O know/O I/O 'm/O going/O to/O get/O it/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O I/O will/O tell/O you/O exactly/O my/O individual/O history/O of/O feeling/O toward/O the/O war/O ./O 
In/O 1958/O ,/O when/O I/O returned/O from/O Thailand/LOCATION ,/O I/O was/O greatly/O concerned/O with/O what/O I/O had/O seen/O as/O an/O almost/O unconscious/O policy/O commitment/O to/O a/O military/O build/O up/O in/O Southeast/LOCATION Asia/LOCATION that/O was/O going/O to/O lead/O to/O a/O major/O ground/O war/O ./O 
I/O made/O those/O statements/O in/O public/O and/O in/O print/O ./O 
And/O I/O made/O those/O --/O that/O observation/O to/O as/O many/O people/O as/O I/O could/O contact/O as/O an/O assistant/O professor/O without/O tenure/O at/O this/O institution/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O also/O felt/O that/O no/O adequate/O explanation/O explaining/O to/O the/O American/O people/O ,/O A/O ,/O that/O this/O was/O in/O the/O offing/O ,/O and/O B/O ,/O its/O precise/O purposes/O was/O ever/O made/O ,/O nor/O has/O it/O been/O made/O ,/O in/O my/O judgment/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O that/O is/O not/O to/O say/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O let/O ,/O let/O ,/O let/O me/O finish/O my/O thought/O here/O ./O 
Um/O --/O HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Please/O ./O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O Well/O ,/O I/O --/O I/O that/O 's/O about/O the/O size/O of/O it/O ,/O I/O guess/O ./O 
That/O 's/O ,/O that/O 's/O the/O way/O I/O felt/O ./O 
Now/O --/O Now/O ,/O I/O --/O my/O views/O ,/O in/O 1970/O ,/O have/O not/O changed/O ./O 
One/O of/O --/O but/O one/O of/O the/O things/O --/O All/O right/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Have/O fun/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O things/O that/O bugs/O me/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O to/O know/O how/O I/O feel/O ,/O is/O that/O there/O is/O an/O assumption/O on/O the/O part/O of/O a/O good/O many/O people/O in/O this/O country/O that/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION and/O the/O Near/LOCATION East/LOCATION is/O a/O matter/O of/O no/O relevance/O ./O 
They/O constantly/O concern/O themselves/O primarily/O with/O European/O policy/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O matter/O --/O it/O is/O inevitable/O ,/O in/O my/O judgment/O ,/O that/O if/O we/O do/O not/O build/O meaningful/O and/O peaceful/O relations/O between/O the/O peoples/O of/O Asia/LOCATION and/O Africa/LOCATION --/O all/O right/O ./O 
Ha/O ,/O ha/O ,/O ha/O ./O 
That/O 's/O funny/O ./O 
Build/O peaceful/O relations/O --/O build/O peaceful/O relations/O with/O these/O people/O ,/O that/O we/O will/O eventually/O be/O destroyed/O by/O our/O own/O thoughtlessness/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O Yeah/O !/O 
JOSEPH/PERSON SUTTON/PERSON :/O But/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O take/O an/O institutional/O stand/O on/O the/O Cambodian/O war/O ./O 
HARRY/PERSON PRATTER/PERSON :/O Just/O --/O ladies/O --/O all/O right/O ./O 
Ladies/O and/O gentlemen/O ,/O originally/O ,/O when/O we/O started/O ,/O I/O said/O we/O would/O run/O for/O an/O hour/O ./O 
We/O 've/O already/O run/O for/O --/O just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
We/O 've/O already/O run/O for/O an/O hour/O and/O 20/O minutes/O ./O 
We/O 'll/O run/O till/O 5:30/O ./O 
And/O I/O want/O to/O recognize/O the/O balcony/O ,/O the/O gentleman/O right/O over/O the/O sign/O there/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O --/O I/O 'm/O sorry/O I/O could/O n't/O see/O you/O before/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Go/O ./O 
AUDIENCE/O :/O I/O have/O one/O question/O for/O President/O Sutton/PERSON ./O 
Why/O is/O legitimate/O dissent/O ,/O i.e./O ,/O campaigning/O for/O your/O congressman/O ?/O 
How/O would/O you/O feel/O about/O implementing/O to/O go/O home/O for/O two/O weeks/O in/O the/O fall/O before/O the/O election/O ?/O 
